<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetadata xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Name>Inspector Plus</Name>
  <ModID>net.inspectorplus</ModID>
  <Author>SixFive7</Author>
  <Version>1.2.0</Version>
  <Description>[h1]Inspector Plus[/h1]

Developer tool that dumps live Stationeers runtime state to JSON on demand for mod development.

Full multiplayer compatibility. Safe to remove from existing savegames.

Not intended for end-user gameplay. Subscribe only if you are writing or debugging a Stationeers mod.

[h2]Features[/h2]

[h3]On-Demand Snapshots via Request JSON[/h3]
Drop a request JSON into [b]BepInEx/inspector/requests/[/b] specifying types and fields to inspect. The plugin writes a snapshot into [b]BepInEx/inspector/snapshots/snapshot_&lt;timestamp&gt;.json[/b] and deletes the request. This is the programmatic path: drop the file, get the result.

[h3]F8 Full-Scene Dump[/h3]
Press F8 in-game to dump every MonoBehaviour in the current scene to the same snapshots folder in one shot. Useful for the first-pass "what is in the scene right now" survey.

[h3]Field, Property, and Unity Position Capture[/h3]
Dumps private and public fields, computed properties, and Unity Transform positions. Walks nested objects to a configurable depth, with cycle detection.

[h3]Headless Server Operation[/h3]
Opt-in: the Force Unpause Without Client setting keeps a headless dedicated server simulating with no client connected, so automated tooling can drop request files and read snapshots without a player joining. The game schedules its own pause a few seconds after world start when no client is connected; while the setting is on that startup pause is skipped, and a watchdog re-asserts the unpause and logs tick state every few seconds. Never affects a client or single-player.

[h2]Settings[/h2]

Settings appear in the StationeersLaunchPad in-game mod settings panel.

[list]
[*][b]Snapshot Key[/b] (Client - Snapshots, default F8): key that writes a full scene snapshot to [b]BepInEx/inspector/snapshots/[/b].
[*][b]Force Unpause Without Client[/b] (Server - Headless, default off): headless dedicated servers only; keep the simulation running with no client connected so request-file snapshots can be captured by automated tooling. Skips the game's startup pause and re-asserts the unpause via a watchdog.
[*][b]Enable Pause Trace Logging[/b] (Server - Headless, default off): dump pause and unpause call-site stack traces to the log to diagnose what re-paused a headless world. Diagnostic for mod developers; noisy around autosaves.
[/list]

[h2]Compatibility[/h2]

[b]Requires:[/b]
[list]
[*][url=https://docs.bepinex.dev/]BepInEx[/url]
[*][url=https://github.com/StationeersLaunchPad/StationeersLaunchPad]StationeersLaunchPad[/url]
[/list]

[b]Single-player and multiplayer.[/b] Works on any instance where it is installed. This is a developer tool; do not require it on a shared server.

[h2]Reporting Issues[/h2]
If you run into a bug or something behaves unexpectedly, please open an issue on [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/issues]GitHub[/url]. Please include the mod name in the title so reports can be triaged. Steam comment notifications don't always come through, so GitHub is the reliable way to make sure a report is seen.

[url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/tree/master/Mods/InspectorPlus]Source Code on GitHub[/url]

[h2]License[/h2]
Licensed under the [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/blob/master/LICENSE]Apache License 2.0[/url]. Attribution required; see the LICENSE and NOTICE files at the repository root.</Description>
  <ChangeLog>
v1.2.0: Headless force-unpause now holds
- Force Unpause Without Client now keeps the simulation running on current game builds: the dedicated server schedules its own pause 5 seconds after world start when no client is connected, which defeated the v1.1.0 one-shot unpause; that startup pause is now skipped while the setting is on.
- While the setting is on, a watchdog re-asserts the unpause and logs tick state every few seconds, so any other silent pause is caught and undone.
- New Enable Pause Trace Logging setting (Server - Headless, off by default) dumps pause and unpause call-site stack traces to the log for diagnosing what re-paused a headless world. Diagnostic for mod developers; noisy around autosaves.
  </ChangeLog>
  <WorkshopHandle>3730349036</WorkshopHandle>
  <Tags>
    <Tag>BepInEx</Tag>
    <Tag>StationeersLaunchPad</Tag>
    <Tag>Tool</Tag>
  </Tags>
  <InGameDescription><![CDATA[<size="30"><color=#ffa500>Inspector Plus</color></size>
<line-height=40%>Developer tool that dumps live Stationeers runtime state to JSON on demand for mod development.
Full multiplayer compatibility. Safe to remove from existing savegames.
<b>Usage:</b> Press F8 in-game for a full MonoBehaviour dump, or drop a request JSON into BepInEx/inspector/requests/ for a targeted snapshot. Output lands in BepInEx/inspector/snapshots/.
<b>Headless:</b> optional Server - Headless settings keep a dedicated server simulating with no client connected, for automated snapshot tooling.
<b>Not intended for end-user gameplay.</b> For modders only.
</line-height>
]]></InGameDescription>
</ModMetadata>
