<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetadata xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Name>Inspector Plus</Name>
  <ModID>net.inspectorplus</ModID>
  <Author>SixFive7</Author>
  <Version>0.2.0</Version>
  <Description>[h1]Inspector Plus[/h1]

Developer tool that dumps live Stationeers runtime state to JSON on demand for mod development.

Not intended for end-user gameplay. Subscribe only if you are writing or debugging a Stationeers mod.

[h2]Features[/h2]

[h3]On-Demand Snapshots via Request JSON[/h3]
Drop a request JSON into [b]BepInEx/inspector/requests/[/b] specifying types and fields to inspect. The plugin writes a snapshot into [b]BepInEx/inspector/snapshots/snapshot_&lt;timestamp&gt;.json[/b] and deletes the request. This is the programmatic path: drop the file, get the result.

[h3]F8 Full-Scene Dump[/h3]
Press F8 in-game to dump every MonoBehaviour in the current scene to the same snapshots folder in one shot. Useful for the first-pass "what is in the scene right now" survey.

[h3]Field, Property, and Unity Position Capture[/h3]
Dumps private and public fields, computed properties, and Unity Transform positions. Walks nested objects to a configurable depth, with cycle detection.

[h2]Compatibility[/h2]

[b]Requires:[/b]
[list]
[*][url=https://docs.bepinex.dev/]BepInEx[/url]
[*][url=https://github.com/StationeersLaunchPad/StationeersLaunchPad]StationeersLaunchPad[/url]
[/list]

[b]Single-player and multiplayer.[/b] Works on any instance where it is installed. This is a developer tool; do not require it on a shared server.

[h2]Reporting Issues[/h2]
If you run into a bug or something behaves unexpectedly, please open an issue on [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/issues]GitHub[/url]. Please include the mod name in the title so reports can be triaged. Steam comment notifications don't always come through, so GitHub is the reliable way to make sure a report is seen.

[url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/tree/master/Mods/InspectorPlus]Source Code on GitHub[/url]

[h2]License[/h2]
Licensed under the [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/blob/master/LICENSE]Apache License 2.0[/url]. Attribution required; see the LICENSE and NOTICE files at the repository root.</Description>
  <ChangeLog>
v0.2.0: Generic walker fixes for any Unity game
- Inline-expand plain serializable classes instead of stringifying them as (TypeName); shared with the UnityEngine.Object path so the same filter, private-include, and skip rules apply
- Null-guard FindObjectsOfType and fall back to a reflection scan over live MonoBehaviours and static members so non-UnityEngine.Object types are still reachable
- Cycle detection via reference-equality set; emit (cycle) when a reference recurs on the same chain
- Hard caps on total serialized bytes, top-level objects, and nested expansions; emit a visible _truncated marker when a cap is hit
- Wrap name, gameObject, activeInHierarchy, transform.position, and other Unity reads in try-catch so destroyed Unity wrappers never throw out of the walker
- Top-level try-catch surfaces unexpected walker errors as an error key in the snapshot JSON
- New maxMonoBehaviours request field (default 10000) lets callers raise or lower the top-level cap

v0.1.0: Initial release
- On-demand snapshots via request JSON drop in BepInEx/inspector/requests/
- F8 full-scene MonoBehaviour dump
- Field, property, and Unity position capture with configurable recursion depth and cycle detection
  </ChangeLog>
  <WorkshopHandle>0</WorkshopHandle>
  <Tags>
    <Tag>BepInEx</Tag>
    <Tag>StationeersLaunchPad</Tag>
    <Tag>Tool</Tag>
  </Tags>
  <InGameDescription><![CDATA[<size="30"><color=#ffa500>Inspector Plus</color></size>
<line-height=40%>Developer tool that dumps live Stationeers runtime state to JSON on demand for mod development.
<b>Usage:</b> Press F8 in-game for a full MonoBehaviour dump, or drop a request JSON into BepInEx/inspector/requests/ for a targeted snapshot. Output lands in BepInEx/inspector/snapshots/.
<b>Not intended for end-user gameplay.</b> For modders only.
</line-height>
]]></InGameDescription>
</ModMetadata>
