<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetadata xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Name>Force Field Door Mod Fix</Name>
  <ModID>net.forcefielddoormodfix</ModID>
  <Author>SixFive7</Author>
  <Version>1.0.1</Version>
  <Description>[h1]No longer needed: ForceFieldDoorMod has been fixed[/h1]

[b]As of 6 July 2026 the original ForceFieldDoorMod has been updated by its author and works on current Stationeers builds on its own. This compatibility fix is no longer required.[/b]

[b]What to do:[/b]
[list]
[*][b]You can safely unsubscribe[/b] from Force Field Door Mod Fix. Nothing else depends on it.
[*][b]It is also safe to leave it enabled.[/b] It automatically detects that ForceFieldDoorMod is fixed and does nothing at all, so it will not interfere with anything.
[/list]

Thanks to the ForceFieldDoorMod author for shipping the proper fix upstream.

[hr][/hr]

[h1]What this mod was[/h1]

A temporary compatibility shim. ForceFieldDoorMod was built against an older Stationeers build and, on 0.2.6403 and later, called a one-argument GridController.CanContainAtmos method the game had removed. That threw a MissingMethodException every atmospheric tick and stopped the whole simulation on any world containing a force field door. This mod took over the door's atmospheric tick and ran a corrected version until the original was updated. That has now happened, so it stands down on its own.

[h2]Compatibility[/h2]

[b]Requires:[/b] BepInEx + StationeersLaunchPad. Works on clients and dedicated servers. No settings.

[h2]Reporting Issues[/h2]
If you run into a bug, please open an issue on [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/issues]GitHub[/url]. Please include the mod name in the title.

[h2]Credits[/h2]
[list]
[*][url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3328065049]ForceFieldDoorMod[/url] by WIKUS and BoNes: the original mod, now fixed by them. All credit for the force field door belongs to them.
[/list]

[url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/tree/master/Mods/ForceFieldDoorModFix]Source Code on GitHub[/url]

[h2]License[/h2]
Licensed under the [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/blob/master/LICENSE]Apache License 2.0[/url]. Attribution required; see the LICENSE and NOTICE files at the repository root.</Description>
  <ChangeLog>
v1.0.1: ForceFieldDoorMod fixed upstream, this mod is no longer needed
- The original ForceFieldDoorMod was updated by its author on 6 July 2026 and now works on current Stationeers builds on its own.
- This compatibility fix is no longer required. You can safely unsubscribe; it is also safe to leave it enabled, since it detects the upstream fix and does nothing.
- Description-only update to inform subscribers. No functional change.
  </ChangeLog>
  <WorkshopHandle>3759105090</WorkshopHandle>
  <Tags>
    <Tag>BepInEx</Tag>
    <Tag>StationeersLaunchPad</Tag>
  </Tags>
  <InGameDescription><![CDATA[<size="32"><color=#ff6666>No longer needed</color></size>
<line-height=40%>ForceFieldDoorMod has been fixed by its author (6 July 2026). This compatibility fix is no longer required.
<b>You can safely unsubscribe.</b> It is also safe to leave it enabled: it detects that ForceFieldDoorMod is fixed and does nothing.
<b>What it was:</b> a temporary shim that kept ForceFieldDoorMod working on 0.2.6403+ until the author updated it.
<b>Requires:</b> BepInEx + StationeersLaunchPad.
<b>Credits:</b> ForceFieldDoorMod by WIKUS and BoNes, now fixed by them.
</line-height>
]]></InGameDescription>
</ModMetadata>
