<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetadata xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Name>Network Purist Plus</Name>
  <ModID>net.networkpuristplus</ModID>
  <Author>SixFive7</Author>
  <Version>1.1.0</Version>
  <Description>[h1]Network Purist Plus[/h1]

Removes the long (3-, 5-, and 10-segment) straight pipe, chute, and super-heavy cable variants and aligns straight cables to one consistent orientation; existing worlds are converted when a save loads.

Full multiplayer compatibility. Safe to add to an existing savegame.

[h2]What it does[/h2]

[h3]Long pieces removed everywhere[/h3]
The merged "long" Straight 3 / 5 / 10 variants are taken out of the game's menus: gas pipes, insulated pipes, liquid pipes, insulated liquid pipes, chutes, and super-heavy cables (the only cable tier with long variants). They are stripped from the build-kit mouse wheel and hidden from the Stationpedia. You build pipes, chutes, and cables one tile at a time, the way it worked before the merge feature was added. The merge-with-a-tool action can no longer produce a long piece either.

[h3]Existing long runs rebuilt on load[/h3]
When a save loads, every already-placed long pipe, chute, or cable run is rebuilt from the equivalent single-tile pieces at the same cells, rotation and custom colour. Networks stay connected, but rebuilt pipe runs start empty -- the gas is not preserved; re-pressurise them. This is a one-time conversion the first time you load a world after installing the mod (and again for any world a long piece sneaks into). A long piece built mid-game (a blueprint paste, another mod) is expanded into single tiles the moment it is built, without waiting for the next world load.

[h3]Cable alignment[/h3]
A straight cable is a tube with a coloured band along the side, but the game lets it be placed at any of four "rolls" about its run direction, so a cable next to one placed a different way shows the band misaligned (most visible on super-heavy cables, and common where zoop-built and hand-built cables meet). This mod picks one orientation per run axis and applies it: every placed straight cable is realigned when a save loads, and a freshly built cable snaps to the canonical orientation the instant it is placed. The rotate key on a cable becomes preview-only. Cosmetic only: connectivity, networks and colour are untouched.

[h3]Plays nicely with drag-build mods[/h3]
[b]ZoopMod[/b]: zooping a long stretch just places single tiles, already lined up. ZoopMod discovers the "long" variants by scanning the build kit's option list, which this mod has emptied of them, so ZoopMod finds none and falls back to single tiles with no error; each tile then goes through the same alignment hook.
[b]BlueprintMod[/b]: a template built before this mod, or from another world, can still contain long pieces. A paste skips the build-time rewrite, so they sit there until the next world load, where the on-load rebuild converts them to single tiles like any other long piece (that rebuild is the universal backstop). Pasted straight cables get re-rolled as they register.
[b]Other build mods[/b] (an "upgrade to a long run" command, the merge-with-a-tool action, a future build mod): this mod never rejects anything -- it rewrites a long-variant placement into single tiles (at build time, or on the next load) and re-rolls a built straight cable. The other mod keeps working; its output just comes out single-tile and consistently oriented, and the on-load rebuild catches anything it missed.

[h2]Settings[/h2]

In the in-game mod settings panel, under [b]Server - Pieces[/b] and [b]Server - Cables[/b]. All server-authoritative: the host's values take effect, and every player and dedicated server must run the same values (a mismatched client is rejected, the same way a version mismatch is). All take effect on a game restart -- the strip / hide / build-cursor work runs once at startup, so toggling one mid-session does nothing until you relaunch.
[list]
[*][b]Enable Network Purist Plus[/b] (default on): master switch -- off means the mod does nothing.
[*][b]Remove Long Gas Pipes[/b] (the basic pipe -- named "Gas Pipe" so it's not confused with the liquid one), [b]Remove Long Liquid Pipes[/b], [b]Remove Long Insulated Gas Pipes[/b], [b]Remove Long Insulated Liquid Pipes[/b], [b]Remove Long Chutes[/b], [b]Remove Long Super-Heavy Cables[/b] (all default on): per-family toggles -- whether that family's long variants are stripped from the kit, hidden from the Stationpedia, rebuilt on load, and rewritten if built mid-game.
[*][b]Align Straight Cables[/b] (default on): re-roll straight cables (all tiers) to one consistent orientation -- existing runs on load, new ones as built, and the cursor for the cable tiers without long variants. Cosmetic only; the cable rotate key becomes preview-only.
[/list]

[h2]Limitations[/h2]
[list]
[*]Rebuilt pipe runs are emptied: the gas inside a long pipe run is deleted when the run is rebuilt from single tiles, by design -- the game's atmospherics-event system loses a pipe network's gas when its pipes are replaced this way, and there is no clean workaround. Re-pressurise the new pipes. Layout, rotation, colour and connectivity are preserved; only the gas is lost. Happens on the first load after installing, and again for any long pipe that enters a world later (NetworkUpgrader, a blueprint paste, the build-time rewrite).
[*]An item physically in transit inside a long chute segment at the moment it is rebuilt is deleted, also by design. Items sitting in chute bins are unaffected.
[*]Straight cables align to each other, but the coloured band can still jump where a straight meets a corner cable: corner pieces have a fixed band orientation and aren't re-rolled (re-rolling a corner would change connectivity, not just looks), and no single per-axis orientation mates with every corner. The mod picks the one that mates with the most.
[*]The rotate key no longer changes a placed straight cable's roll -- a built cable always snaps to the canonical orientation for its run axis. This is the cable-alignment feature; it affects the build preview, not gameplay.
[/list]

[h2]Compatibility[/h2]

[b]Requires:[/b]
[list]
[*][url=https://docs.bepinex.dev/]BepInEx[/url]
[*][url=https://github.com/StationeersLaunchPad/StationeersLaunchPad]StationeersLaunchPad[/url]
[/list]

[b]Compatible with[/b] ZoopMod, BlueprintMod, NetworkUpgrader, the "no tool required for pipe/cable merging" mods, and other build mods. No patch conflict -- this mod's Harmony patches sit on methods none of those touch -- and it stays compatible by design with any mod that creates a wrong-length or wrong-orientation segment, because it never rejects anything, it rewrites and re-rolls. See "Plays nicely with drag-build mods" above for the how (ZoopMod, BlueprintMod, and the general case).

[b]Network enforcement:[/b] every player and dedicated server on a multiplayer game must run the same version of Network Purist Plus AND the same settings. A client without the mod, with a different version, or with different settings is rejected at join time with a clear message -- the build-kit option lists and the Stationpedia are reshaped at prefab-load time, before any client joins, so a mismatch would desync the build wheel. [b]Dedicated servers[/b] need the same BepInEx + StationeersLaunchPad + Network Purist Plus setup with the same settings; the server's copy is the one that rebuilds the world.

[h2]Reporting Issues[/h2]
If you run into a bug or something behaves unexpectedly, please open an issue on [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/issues]GitHub[/url], with "[Network Purist Plus]" in the title so it can be triaged. Steam comment notifications are unreliable, so GitHub is the way to make sure a report is seen.

[url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/tree/master/Mods/NetworkPuristPlus]Source Code on GitHub[/url]

[h2]License[/h2]
Licensed under the [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/blob/master/LICENSE]Apache License 2.0[/url]. Attribution required; see the LICENSE and NOTICE files at the repository root.</Description>
  <ChangeLog>
v1.1.0: Settings panel, network enforcement, cable alignment, build-time long-piece rewrite
- Added a settings panel (in the in-game mod settings, under Server - Pieces and Server - Cables): a master Enable Network Purist Plus toggle, per-family long-piece toggles (Remove Long Gas Pipes, Remove Long Liquid Pipes, Remove Long Insulated Gas Pipes, Remove Long Insulated Liquid Pipes, Remove Long Chutes, Remove Long Super-Heavy Cables), and an Align Straight Cables toggle. All default on. All server-authoritative -- the host's values take effect. All of them take effect on a game restart: the strip / hide / build-cursor work runs once at startup, so toggling one mid-session does nothing until you relaunch (the in-game panel marks them with a restart indicator). The pipe-family toggle names spell out "Gas Pipe" / "Insulated Gas Pipe" even though the game's own term for the basic pipe is just "Pipe" -- otherwise you couldn't tell the gas toggle from the liquid one.
- Network enforcement (via LaunchPadBooster): every player and dedicated server on a multiplayer game must run the same version AND the same settings. A client without the mod, with a different version, or with different settings is rejected at join time with a clear message. Necessary because the build-kit options and the Stationpedia are reshaped at prefab-load time, before any client joins.
- Straight cables (all tiers) are aligned to one consistent orientation per run axis: every already-placed straight cable is realigned when a world loads, and a freshly built cable snaps to the canonical orientation the moment it is placed. Fixes the misaligned-band look on cable runs (most visible on super-heavy cables, common where zoop-built and hand-built cables meet). Cosmetic only -- connectivity, networks and colour are untouched. The rotate key on a cable becomes preview-only. The chosen orientation is the one that mates with the most corner pieces; the coloured band can still jump where a straight meets a corner cable (corner pieces have a fixed band orientation and aren't re-rolled, and no single per-axis orientation mates with every corner) -- a full corner-seam fix is planned as a future change.
- A long piece that appears mid-game (a blueprint paste, another mod) is now expanded into single tiles the moment it is built, instead of only being caught on the next world load.
- The single-tile straight pipe, cable and chute in each build kit is given the "straight" connection type, which makes the build cursor and the smart-rotate cycle consistent and keeps the merge-with-tool action working now that the long straight variants are gone from the kits (without that, merging two collinear pipes or cables with the tool throws an error).
- Belt-and-suspenders: a Harmony postfix on the Stationpedia page-override pass re-asserts the hidden flag on the removed long variants, in case a future mod's page override would clear it.
- Compatible with ZoopMod, BlueprintMod, NetworkUpgrader and other build mods: no patch conflict (this mod's Harmony patches are on methods none of them patch), and the mod never rejects anything -- it rewrites a long-variant placement into single tiles (at build time, or on the next world load) and re-rolls a built straight cable -- so those mods keep working and just produce single-tile, consistently oriented pieces.

v1.0.0: Initial release
- Removes the long straight pipe, insulated pipe, liquid pipe, insulated liquid pipe, chute, and super-heavy cable variants (the 3, 5, and 10-segment pieces) from the build-kit mouse wheel and hides them from the Stationpedia.
- On save load, rebuilds every already-placed long run from single-tile pieces at the same cells, rotation, and colour, keeping networks connected. Rebuilt pipe runs start empty (gas contents are not preserved); re-pressurise them.
- Compatible with ZoopMod (zooping a long stretch produces single-tile pieces) and NetworkUpgrader.
- Known limitations: a rebuilt pipe run starts empty; an item physically in transit inside a long chute segment is lost when that segment is rebuilt.
  </ChangeLog>
  <WorkshopHandle>0</WorkshopHandle>
  <Tags>
    <Tag>BepInEx</Tag>
    <Tag>StationeersLaunchPad</Tag>
  </Tags>
  <InGameDescription><![CDATA[<size="30"><color=#ffa500>Network Purist Plus</color></size>
<line-height=40%>Keep your pipe, chute and cable networks tidy: no oversized "long" prefabs, every straight cable lined up the same. Full multiplayer compatibility; safe on an existing save.
<b>What it does:</b>
- The long Straight 3/5/10 variants (pipes of all kinds, chutes, super-heavy cables) are removed from the build kit and Stationpedia; placed long runs are rebuilt from single tiles on load (networks intact), and a mid-game long piece is rewritten at once.
- Straight cables (all tiers) are aligned to one orientation per run axis -- existing runs on load, new ones as built. Cosmetic; the cable rotate key becomes preview-only.
<b>Works with</b> ZoopMod (zooping places single tiles, already aligned -- the long variants are gone from the kit) and BlueprintMod (a pasted long piece is converted on the next world load); no patch conflict.
<b>Limitations:</b> a rebuilt pipe run starts empty (re-pressurise it); an item in transit inside a long chute is lost when rebuilt; the band can still jump where a straight meets a corner.
<b>Settings:</b> master enable + per-family long-piece toggles + cable alignment, server-authoritative; a change needs a game restart.
<b>Requires:</b> BepInEx + StationeersLaunchPad. All players and the server need the same version and settings; a mismatched client is rejected on join.
</line-height>
]]></InGameDescription>
</ModMetadata>
