<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetadata xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Name>Network Purist Plus</Name>
  <ModID>net.networkpuristplus</ModID>
  <Author>SixFive7</Author>
  <Version>1.1.0</Version>
  <Description>[h1]Network Purist Plus[/h1]

Removes the long (3-, 5-, and 10-segment) straight pipe, chute, and super-heavy cable variants and aligns straight cables to one consistent orientation; existing worlds are converted when a save loads.

Full multiplayer compatibility. Safe to add to an existing savegame.

[h2]What it does[/h2]

[h3]Long pieces removed everywhere[/h3]
The merged "long" straight variants are taken out of the game's menus:
[list]
[*]Gas pipes, insulated pipes, liquid pipes, and insulated liquid pipes: the Straight 3 / 5 / 10 variants.
[*]Chutes: the Straight 3 / 5 / 10 variants.
[*]Super-heavy cables: the Straight 3 / 5 / 10 variants (the only cable tier that has long variants).
[/list]
They are stripped from the build-kit mouse wheel and hidden from the Stationpedia. You build pipes, chutes, and cables one tile at a time, the way it worked before the merge feature was added. The merge-with-a-tool action can no longer produce a long piece either.

[h3]Existing long runs rebuilt on load[/h3]
When a save loads, every already-placed long pipe, chute, or cable run is rebuilt from the equivalent single-tile pieces at the same cells, with the same rotation and custom colour. Networks stay connected, but rebuilt pipe runs start empty -- the gas inside a long pipe run is not preserved; re-pressurise them. This is a one-time conversion the first time you load a world after installing the mod (and again for any world a long piece sneaks into). A long piece that turns up mid-game (a blueprint paste, another mod) is expanded into single tiles the moment it is built, so it does not have to wait for the next world load.

[h3]Cable alignment[/h3]
Straight cables are a tube with a coloured band along the side, but the game lets a straight cable be placed at any of four "rolls" about its run direction, so a cable next to one placed a different way shows the band misaligned. (You see it most with super-heavy cables, and it crops up easily when zoop-built and hand-built cables meet, or after pressing the rotate key.) This mod picks one orientation per run axis and applies it: every already-placed straight cable is realigned when a save loads, and a freshly built cable snaps to the canonical orientation the instant it is placed (so building with ZoopMod, pasting a blueprint, or rotating the cursor all still work, they just produce an aligned cable). The rotate key on a cable becomes preview-only as a result. This is cosmetic only: connectivity, networks, colour and everything else are untouched.

[h3]Plays nicely with drag-build mods[/h3]
With ZoopMod installed, zooping a long stretch of pipe, chute, or cable just places single-tile pieces instead of the long variants, already at the canonical roll for cables. NetworkUpgrader's "upgrade" command and the in-game merge tool likewise can no longer create long pieces.

[h2]Settings[/h2]

In the in-game mod settings panel, under [b]Server - Pieces[/b] and [b]Server - Cables[/b]. All server-authoritative: the host's values take effect, and every player (and dedicated server) must run the same values -- a joining client whose settings differ is rejected, the same way a version mismatch is. A setting change takes effect on the next restart.
[list]
[*][b]Enable Network Purist Plus[/b] (default on): master switch -- off means the mod does nothing.
[*][b]Remove Long Gas Pipes[/b], [b]Remove Long Liquid Pipes[/b], [b]Remove Long Insulated Pipes[/b], [b]Remove Long Chutes[/b], [b]Remove Long Super-Heavy Cables[/b] (all default on): per-family toggles -- whether that family's long variants are stripped from the kit, hidden from the Stationpedia, rebuilt on load, and rewritten if built mid-game.
[*][b]Align Straight Cables[/b] (default on): re-roll straight cables (all tiers) to one consistent orientation -- existing runs on load, new ones as built, and the cursor for the cable tiers without long variants. Cosmetic only; the cable rotate key becomes preview-only.
[/list]

[h2]Limitations[/h2]
[list]
[*]Rebuilt pipe runs are emptied: the gas inside a long pipe run is deleted when the run is rebuilt from single tiles. This is by design, not a bug being chased -- the game's atmospherics-event system loses a pipe network's gas when its pipes are replaced this way, and there is no clean workaround. Re-pressurise the new single-tile pipes. Layout, rotation, colour and network connectivity are preserved; only the gas is lost. It happens on the first load after installing the mod, and again for any long pipe that enters a world later (NetworkUpgrader, a blueprint paste, or the build-time rewrite).
[*]An item physically in transit inside a long chute segment at the moment it is rebuilt is deleted, also by design. Items sitting in chute bins are unaffected.
[*]The rotate key no longer changes a placed straight cable's roll -- a built cable always snaps to the canonical orientation for its run axis. This is the cable-alignment feature; it affects the cable build preview, not gameplay.
[/list]

[h2]Compatibility[/h2]

[b]Requires:[/b]
[list]
[*][url=https://docs.bepinex.dev/]BepInEx[/url]
[*][url=https://github.com/StationeersLaunchPad/StationeersLaunchPad]StationeersLaunchPad[/url]
[/list]

[b]Compatible with[/b] ZoopMod and BlueprintMod: this mod's Harmony patches sit on methods neither of those mods patches, so there is no patch conflict; they keep working and just produce single-tile, aligned pieces. Also fine alongside NetworkUpgrader and the "no tool required for pipe/cable merging" mods (none of which can create long pieces while this mod is active).

[b]Network enforcement:[/b] every player (and dedicated server) on a multiplayer game must run the same version of Network Purist Plus AND the same settings. A client without the mod, with a different version, or with different settings is rejected at join time with a clear message -- the build-kit option lists and the Stationpedia are reshaped at prefab-load time, before any client joins, so a mismatch would desync what each player sees in their build wheel. [b]Dedicated servers[/b] need the same BepInEx + StationeersLaunchPad + Network Purist Plus setup installed server-side, with the same settings as the connecting players; the server's copy is the one that rebuilds the world.

[h2]Reporting Issues[/h2]
If you run into a bug or something behaves unexpectedly, please open an issue on [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/issues]GitHub[/url], with "[Network Purist Plus]" in the title so it can be triaged. Steam comment notifications are unreliable, so GitHub is the way to make sure a report is seen.

[url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/tree/master/Mods/NetworkPuristPlus]Source Code on GitHub[/url]

[h2]License[/h2]
Licensed under the [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/blob/master/LICENSE]Apache License 2.0[/url]. Attribution required; see the LICENSE and NOTICE files at the repository root.</Description>
  <ChangeLog>
v1.1.0: Settings panel, network enforcement, cable alignment, build-time long-piece rewrite
- Added a settings panel (in the in-game mod settings, under Server - Pieces and Server - Cables): a master Enable Network Purist Plus toggle, per-family long-piece toggles (gas pipes, liquid pipes, insulated pipes, chutes, super-heavy cables), and an Align Straight Cables toggle. All default on. All server-authoritative -- the host's values take effect.
- Network enforcement (via LaunchPadBooster): every player and dedicated server on a multiplayer game must run the same version AND the same settings. A client without the mod, with a different version, or with different settings is rejected at join time with a clear message. Necessary because the build-kit options and the Stationpedia are reshaped at prefab-load time, before any client joins.
- Straight cables (all tiers) are aligned to one consistent orientation per run axis: every already-placed straight cable is realigned when a world loads, and a freshly built cable snaps to the canonical orientation the moment it is placed. Fixes the misaligned-band look on cable runs (most visible on super-heavy cables, common where zoop-built and hand-built cables meet). Cosmetic only -- connectivity, networks and colour are untouched. The rotate key on a cable becomes preview-only.
- A long piece that appears mid-game (a blueprint paste, another mod) is now expanded into single tiles the moment it is built, instead of only being caught on the next world load.
- The single-tile straight pipe, cable and chute in each build kit is given the "straight" connection type, which makes the build cursor and the smart-rotate cycle consistent and keeps the merge-with-tool action working now that the long straight variants are gone from the kits (without that, merging two collinear pipes or cables with the tool throws an error).
- Belt-and-suspenders: a Harmony postfix on the Stationpedia page-override pass re-asserts the hidden flag on the removed long variants, in case a future mod's page override would clear it.
- Verified compatible with ZoopMod and BlueprintMod: this mod's Harmony patches are on methods neither of those mods patches; no patch conflict.

v1.0.0: Initial release
- Removes the long straight pipe, insulated pipe, liquid pipe, insulated liquid pipe, chute, and super-heavy cable variants (the 3, 5, and 10-segment pieces) from the build-kit mouse wheel and hides them from the Stationpedia.
- On save load, rebuilds every already-placed long run from single-tile pieces at the same cells, rotation, and colour, keeping networks connected. Rebuilt pipe runs start empty (gas contents are not preserved); re-pressurise them.
- Compatible with ZoopMod (zooping a long stretch produces single-tile pieces) and NetworkUpgrader.
- Known limitations: a rebuilt pipe run starts empty; an item physically in transit inside a long chute segment is lost when that segment is rebuilt.
  </ChangeLog>
  <WorkshopHandle>0</WorkshopHandle>
  <Tags>
    <Tag>BepInEx</Tag>
    <Tag>StationeersLaunchPad</Tag>
  </Tags>
  <InGameDescription><![CDATA[<size="30"><color=#ffa500>Network Purist Plus</color></size>
<line-height=40%>Removes the long (3-, 5-, and 10-segment) straight pipe, chute, and super-heavy cable variants and aligns straight cables to one consistent orientation; existing worlds are converted when a save loads.
Full multiplayer compatibility. Safe to add to an existing savegame.
<b>What it does:</b>
- The long Straight 3 / 5 / 10 variants of pipes, insulated pipes, liquid pipes, chutes, and super-heavy cables are removed from the build-kit wheel and the Stationpedia; placed long runs are rebuilt from single tiles on load (networks stay connected) and a long piece built mid-game is rewritten immediately.
- Straight cables (all tiers) are aligned to one orientation per run axis -- existing runs on load, new ones as built -- so the band stops looking misaligned. Cosmetic; the cable rotate key becomes preview-only. Works with ZoopMod and BlueprintMod (no patch conflict).
<b>Limitations:</b> a rebuilt pipe run starts empty (re-pressurise it); an item in transit inside a long chute is lost when that segment is rebuilt.
<b>Settings:</b> master enable + per-family long-piece toggles + cable alignment, all server-authoritative.
<b>Requires:</b> BepInEx + StationeersLaunchPad. All players and dedicated servers need the same version AND settings; a mismatched client is rejected on join.
</line-height>
]]></InGameDescription>
</ModMetadata>
