<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetadata xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Name>Spray Paint Plus</Name>
  <ModID>net.spraypaintplus</ModID>
  <Author>SixFive7</Author>
  <Version>1.6.0</Version>
  <Description>[h1]Spray Paint Plus[/h1]

Combines [b]color cycling[/b], [b]network painting[/b], [b]glow paint[/b], and [b]infinite spray paint[/b] into one multiplayer-safe Stationeers mod.

Builds on the excellent work of [b]Elmotrix[/b] ([url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3163662298]Color Cycler[/url], [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2876605527]Network Painter[/url]) and [b]Aspct[/b] ([url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3576112002]Infinite Spray Paint[/url]), whose original mods inspired this project. The multiplayer networking code in Color Cycler was contributed by [b]SubHobo[/b] (bls220). Spray Paint Plus combines their ideas and fixes the multiplayer issues that affected clients in those mods.

[h2]Features[/h2]

[h3]Full Multiplayer Support[/h3]
All features work correctly for every player, host and clients alike. Late-joining players see the correct spray can colors immediately.

[h3]Color Cycling[/h3]
Scroll your mouse wheel while holding a spray can to cycle through all available paint colors. No more carrying twelve cans in a backpack.

[h3]Infinite Spray Paint[/h3]
All spray cans have unlimited uses and produce no pollution. Both are configurable.

[h3]Network Painting[/h3]
Spray-paint a pipe, cable, chute, or robotic arm rail and the entire connected network gets painted at once.
[list]
[*][b]Hold Shift[/b] to paint just a single item (or swap this default, see Settings)
[*][b]Hold Ctrl[/b] for a checkered/alternating paint pattern
[*]Works on: pipe networks (including hydroponic trays and passive vents as separate paint groups), cable networks, chute networks, and robotic arm rail assemblies (rails, junctions, bypass pieces, and docks)
[/list]

[h3]Room &amp; Structure Painting[/h3]
Spray-paint a wall and every same-type wall bounding the same room is painted. Spray-paint a frame, girder, or any other large structure and all orthogonally-connected structures of the same exact type are painted with it.
[list]
[*]Walls use the game's Room membership to decide the paint set. Paint spills across any wall the room touches, but never past a doorway into another room
[*]Large structures flood-fill on a grid using 6-neighbor (cardinal) adjacency only; diagonals are not followed
[*]Same Shift / Ctrl modifiers apply
[/list]

[h3]Glow Paint[/h3]
The [b]Spray Paint Gun[/b] becomes a self-contained glow applicator. Point at any painted target and fire; the target keeps its existing color and gains a glow halo, visible in unlit rooms. Every vanilla paint color supports glow.
[list]
[*]Gun is ammo-less. It no longer accepts spray cans; loading one is blocked at the UI and at the server
[*]Gun never changes a target's color. To change color, paint with a plain can first; then fire the gun to add glow
[*]Shift (single target) and Ctrl (checkered pattern) modifiers apply to gun-paint too
[*]Right-click the gun to switch between [b]Add Glow[/b] and [b]Remove Glow[/b] modes (vanilla on/off toggle, HUD label rebranded)
[*]Color and glow are orthogonal: a can paint only changes color, a gun fire only changes glow
[*]Glow state persists across save/load and syncs correctly in multiplayer; every connected player sees the same glowing targets
[*]Server toggle "Enable Glow Paint" lets admins disable the feature; when off, the gun reverts to the vanilla can-accepting behavior
[/list]

[h3]Safe to Uninstall[/h3]
Saves written by v1.6.0+ open cleanly without this mod installed; glow state lives in a side-car the vanilla loader ignores. Re-install later and load a pre-removal save to restore glow.

[h3]Settings[/h3]

All features are configurable via the mod settings panel.

[b]Client - Preferences[/b] (personal preference, each player sets independently):
[list]
[*][b]Paint Single Item By Default[/b] (default Off): Swap Shift behavior, single paint by default, hold Shift for network paint
[*][b]Invert Color Scroll Direction[/b] (default Off): Reverse the scroll wheel direction
[/list]

[b]Server - Consumables[/b] (the host's value controls gameplay for everyone):
[list]
[*][b]Unlimited Spray Paint Uses[/b] (default On): Infinite spray cans
[*][b]Suppress Spray Paint Pollution[/b] (default On): No pollutant gas when spraying
[/list]

[b]Server - Glow Paint[/b]:
[list]
[*][b]Enable Glow Paint[/b] (default On): The Spray Paint Gun adds glow to painted targets without changing color, and the gun no longer accepts spray cans. When off, the gun reverts to its vanilla behavior (accepts and uses loaded spray cans as ammo)
[/list]

[b]Server - Network Painting[/b]:
[list]
[*][b]Enable Network Painting[/b] (default On): Paint entire networks at once
[*][b]Network Paint Pipes[/b] (default On): Include pipes in network painting
[*][b]Network Paint Cables[/b] (default On): Include cables in network painting
[*][b]Network Paint Chutes[/b] (default On): Include chutes in network painting
[*][b]Network Paint Walls[/b] (default On): Paint all same-type walls bounding the same room
[*][b]Network Paint Rails[/b] (default On): Paint every rail, junction, bypass, and dock on the same robotic arm assembly in one stroke
[*][b]Network Paint Large Structures[/b] (default On): Paint connected frames, girders, and other large structures in a 6-neighbor grid
[/list]

[h2]Compatibility[/h2]

[b]Requires:[/b]
[list]
[*][url=https://docs.bepinex.dev/]BepInEx[/url]
[*][url=https://github.com/StationeersLaunchPad/StationeersLaunchPad]StationeersLaunchPad[/url]
[/list]

[b]Incompatible with[/b] (detected at startup; the mod refuses to load if either is found):
[list]
[*][url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3163662298]Color Cycler[/url] by Elmotrix
[*][url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2876605527]Network Painter[/url] by Elmotrix
[/list]

[b]Redundant[/b] (disable if installed): [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3576112002]Infinite Spray Paint[/url] by Aspct, [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1761980496]Infinite Paint Mod[/url] by Dingo.

[b]All players[/b] (including dedicated-server operators) need the same BepInEx + StationeersLaunchPad + Spray Paint Plus setup. Matching versions are enforced during the connection handshake.

[h2]Reporting Issues[/h2]
If you run into a bug or something behaves unexpectedly, please open an issue on [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/issues]GitHub[/url]. Please include the mod name in the title so reports can be triaged. Steam comment notifications don't always come through, so GitHub is the reliable way to make sure a report is seen.

[h2]Credits[/h2]

Spray Paint Plus would not exist without the modders who came before:
[list]
[*][b]Elmotrix[/b]: Created [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3163662298]Color Cycler[/url] and [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2876605527]Network Painter[/url], the original spray paint enhancement mods for Stationeers. The core ideas of scroll-to-cycle and paint-entire-networks are theirs.
[*][b]SubHobo[/b] (bls220): Contributed the initial multiplayer networking code to Color Cycler via [url=https://github.com/Elmotrix/ColorCyclerMod/pull/1]PR #1[/url].
[*][b]Aspct[/b]: Created [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3576112002]Infinite Spray Paint[/url], the original clean infinite paint mod for Stationeers.
[*][b]Dingo (DingoPD)[/b]: Created the original [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1761980496]Infinite Paint Mod[/url], the first infinite spray paint mod for Stationeers.
[/list]

[url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/tree/master/Mods/SprayPaintPlus]Source Code on GitHub[/url]

[h2]License[/h2]
Licensed under the [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/blob/master/LICENSE]Apache License 2.0[/url]. Attribution required; see the LICENSE and NOTICE files at the repository root.</Description>
  <ChangeLog>
v1.6.0: Clean uninstall for saves with glow paint
- Glow state now persists in a side-car file (sprayplus-glow.xml) inside the save ZIP, instead of a custom ThingSaveData subclass inside world.xml
- Removing the mod from a save is now safe: the side-car is silently ignored on load, glow is lost but the save still opens
- Before v1.6.0, a save that used glow paint could not be loaded without the mod installed; the XmlSerializer refused the unknown xsi:type and the whole world.xml failed to deserialize
- Migration is automatic: loading a pre-v1.6.0 save reads the old GlowThingSaveData entries for back-compat; the next save writes the new side-car format and rewrites world.xml without the custom xsi:type
- No gameplay change, no multiplayer protocol change
- REQUIRES: All players on a server must run 1.6.0 (matching-version handshake)

v1.5.2: Sync release alongside the repo-wide About.xml size-cap rule
- No code or content changes since v1.5.1
- Workshop Description verified at 7962/8000 characters under the newly-documented repo rule
- REQUIRES: All players on a server must run 1.5.2 (matching-version handshake)

v1.5.1: Fix Workshop description layout broken by oversized Settings preamble
- The v1.5.0 Settings section added a long explanatory preamble paragraph that pushed the Workshop description past Steam's character limit and broke the layout on the Workshop page
- Dropped the preamble; the four Scope - Topic headers keep the same grouping and ordering as v1.5.0 (Client - Preferences, Server - Consumables, Server - Glow Paint, Server - Network Painting)
- No gameplay change, no multiplayer protocol change
- REQUIRES: All players on a server must run 1.5.1 (matching-version handshake)

v1.5.0: Reorganize in-game settings panel into Scope - &lt;Topic&gt; groups
- The twelve settings now live in four collapsible groups: Client - Preferences (Paint Single Item By Default, Invert Color Scroll Direction), Server - Consumables (Unlimited Spray Paint Uses, Suppress Spray Paint Pollution), Server - Glow Paint (Enable Glow Paint), Server - Network Painting (Enable Network Painting, Network Paint Pipes / Cables / Chutes / Walls / Rails / Large Structures)
- Entries within each group use a deliberate order instead of alphabetical (master toggle first, utility networks before structural networks, primary tweaks before secondary)
- Existing player configuration values reset to defaults on first launch after updating. The section names changed, so BepInEx treats the old stored values as orphaned and re-seeds with defaults
- No gameplay change, no multiplayer protocol change
- REQUIRES: All players on a server must run 1.5.0 (matching-version handshake)

v1.4.0: Glow paint gun
- NEW: The Spray Paint Gun is now a self-contained glow applicator. Fire at a painted target and it gains a glow halo (emissive material, visible as a bloom halo in unlit rooms); target's existing color is preserved
- NEW: Right-click the gun to switch between Add Glow and Remove Glow modes (repurposes the vanilla on/off toggle, with the HUD label rebranded)
- CHANGE: The gun no longer accepts spray cans. The gun has no ammo requirement and its can slot is hidden in the inventory UI
- Color and glow are orthogonal: a can paint only changes color, a gun fire only changes glow
- Shift (single target) and Ctrl (checkered pattern) modifiers apply to gun-paint
- Glow state persists across save/load and syncs correctly in multiplayer; works on every vanilla paint color
- NEW: Server toggle "Enable Glow Paint" (default On); when off, the gun reverts to accepting cans and painting their color
- REQUIRES: All players on a server must run 1.4.0 (matching-version handshake)

v1.3.0: Paint whole robotic arm rail assemblies
- NEW: Painting any rail piece, junction, bypass, or dock paints every member of the same robotic arm assembly in one stroke
- NEW: Server toggle "Network Paint Rails" (default On)
- Shift still restricts to the single targeted piece; Ctrl still produces a checkered pattern
- REQUIRES: All players on a server must run 1.3.0 (matching-version handshake)

v1.2.5: Repoint Reporting Issues and Source Code URLs at the StationeersPlus monorepo
- The Reporting Issues link in the About description now points at github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/issues
- The Source Code link now points at github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/tree/master/Mods/SprayPaintPlus
- No gameplay changes
- REQUIRES: All players on a server must run 1.2.5 (matching-version handshake)

v1.2.4: Patch release
- REQUIRES: All players on a server must run 1.2.4 (matching-version handshake)

v1.2.3: Refreshed Steam Workshop preview art
- Replaced the preview and thumbnail images with a new 16:9 key art that showcases the mod's features (color cycling, infinite paint, network painting, Shift/Ctrl modifiers, multiplayer)
- No gameplay changes
- REQUIRES: All players on a server must run 1.2.3 (matching-version handshake)

v1.2.2: Infinite spray fix for single-player
- FIX: Infinite spray paint now works in solo play. The server-only guard was also catching single-player (which the game reports as neither server nor client), so the infinite/suppress logic was silently skipped outside multiplayer.
- REQUIRES: All players on a server must run 1.2.2 (matching-version handshake)

v1.2.1: Ctrl-checkered fix for walls and large structures
- FIX: Ctrl now produces a proper alternating pattern on walls and large structures. Previously every candidate landed on the same cell-parity, so the checker filter painted the whole set.
- REQUIRES: All players on a server must run 1.2.1 (matching-version handshake)

v1.2.0: Paint whole rooms and whole frame grids
- NEW: Painting a wall now paints all same-type walls bounding the same room
- NEW: Painting a frame, girder, or other large structure paints all orthogonally-connected structures of the exact same type
- NEW: Server toggles "Network Paint Walls" and "Network Paint Large Structures" (both default on)
- Shift still restricts to the single targeted item; Ctrl still produces a checkered pattern

v1.1.1: Modifier keys for clients
- FIX: Shift / Ctrl modifiers now apply correctly when remote clients paint. Previously the server read the host's keyboard for every client's paint action, so clients' modifiers were ignored (always behaved as if nothing was held)
- Skip redundant client-side network-paint prefix for non-spray paint paths (cosmetic-only, did not propagate)
- REQUIRES: All players on a server must run 1.1.1 (wire format change in the modifier message)

v1.1.0: LaunchPadBooster Networking V2
- CHANGE: Migrated to the new Networking V2 API (dedicated channel, automatic compression, multi-packet splitting)
- CHANGE: Explicitly enforce matching mod versions during the multiplayer handshake
- REQUIRES: StationeersLaunchPad with LaunchPadBooster v0.2.0 or newer

v1.0.0: Initial release
- Combines Color Cycler, Network Painter, and Infinite Spray Paint into one multiplayer-safe mod
- Scroll to cycle spray can colors; hold Shift to paint a single item; hold Ctrl for checkered pattern
- Network painting for pipes, cables, and chutes with per-type toggles
- Infinite spray paint uses and pollution suppression (server-side toggles)
- Conflict detection against the three original mods
  </ChangeLog>
  <WorkshopHandle>3702940349</WorkshopHandle>
  <Tags>
    <Tag>BepInEx</Tag>
    <Tag>StationeersLaunchPad</Tag>
    <Tag>paint</Tag>
    <Tag>multiplayer</Tag>
  </Tags>
  <InGameDescription><![CDATA[<size="30"><color=#ffa500>Spray Paint Plus</color></size>
Combines color cycling, network painting, glow paint, and infinite spray paint into one multiplayer-safe Stationeers mod.

<b>Features:</b>
- Full multiplayer support: all players see consistent paint results
- Scroll wheel to cycle spray can colors
- Infinite spray paint uses (configurable)
- No spray paint pollution (configurable)
- Spray paints entire pipe/cable/chute networks (hydroponic trays and passive vents form separate paint groups)
- Spray paints all same-type walls bounding the same room
- Spray paints connected frames, girders, and other large structures in a 6-neighbor grid
- Spray paints whole robotic arm rail assemblies (rails, junctions, bypass pieces, docks)
- Paint with the Spray Paint Gun to add glow to existing paint (ammo-less; does not change color; cans no longer loadable)
- Hold Shift to paint single item (or swap with config)
- Hold Ctrl for checkered pattern
- Safe to uninstall: saves written by v1.6.0+ open without this mod installed; glow state lives in a side-car the vanilla loader ignores

<b>Settings:</b>
All features are configurable via the mod settings panel.
Server settings control gameplay for all players.
Client settings (scroll direction, single/network default) are personal.

<b>Requirements:</b> BepInEx + StationeersLaunchPad

<b>Multiplayer:</b> All players must have this mod installed. Matching mod versions are enforced during the connection handshake automatically. Dedicated servers need the same setup installed server-side.

<b>Incompatible with</b> (mod refuses to load if either is found): Color Cycler, Network Painter (both by Elmotrix).
<b>Redundant</b> (disable if installed): Infinite Spray Paint by Aspct, Infinite Paint Mod by Dingo.
]]></InGameDescription>
</ModMetadata>
