<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetadata xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Name>Spray Paint Plus</Name>
  <ModID>net.spraypaintplus</ModID>
  <Author>SixFive7</Author>
  <Version>1.10.0</Version>
  <Description>[h1]Spray Paint Plus[/h1]

Combines [b]color cycling[/b], [b]network painting[/b], [b]glow paint[/b], and [b]infinite spray paint[/b] into one multiplayer-safe Stationeers mod.

Full multiplayer compatibility. Safe to remove from existing savegames.

[h2]Features[/h2]

[h3]Full Multiplayer Support[/h3]
Works for host and clients alike; late joiners immediately see the correct spray can colors.

[h3]Color Cycling[/h3]
Scroll your mouse wheel while holding a spray can to cycle through all paint colors. No more carrying twelve cans in a backpack.

[h3]Color Picking (Eyedropper)[/h3]
Right-click any paintable object with a spray can in hand to copy its color onto the can. Left-click the next item to match.
[list]
[*][b]Ctrl+right-click[/b] picks the as-built kit color, ignoring any later repaint
[*][b]Shift+right-click[/b] is reserved (currently no-op)
[*]Works on any paintable object
[/list]

[h3]Infinite Spray Paint[/h3]
Spray cans have unlimited uses and produce no pollution. Both are configurable.

[h3]Network Painting[/h3]
Spray-paint one piece of a connected network and the whole network gets painted at once.
[list]
[*][b]Hold Shift[/b] to paint just a single item (or swap this default, see Settings)
[*][b]Hold Ctrl[/b] for a checkered/alternating paint pattern
[*]Works on pipe networks (hydroponic trays and passive vents paint separately), cable networks, chute networks, robotic arm rail assemblies, and elevators (the carriage is painted separately)
[*]Stairs connect every flight of a continuous staircase; stairwells connect every adjacent block, all eight types and any orientation; ladders connect the column, end caps included
[/list]

[h3]Room &amp; Structure Painting[/h3]
Spray-paint a wall and every same-type wall bounding the same room is painted. Spray-paint a frame, girder, or any other large structure and all orthogonally-connected structures of the same exact type are painted with it.
[list]
[*]Walls flood by Room membership: paint spills across the room's walls but never past a doorway
[*]Large structures flood-fill on a grid using 6-neighbor (cardinal) adjacency only; diagonals are not followed
[*]Same Shift / Ctrl modifiers apply
[/list]

[h3]Glow Paint[/h3]
The [b]Spray Paint Gun[/b] becomes a glow applicator: fire at a painted target to add a glow halo (visible in unlit rooms) while keeping its color. Every paint color supports glow.
[list]
[*]Gun is ammo-less. It no longer accepts spray cans; its can slot is hidden in the inventory
[*]Gun never changes a target's color. To change color, paint with a plain can first, then fire the gun to add glow
[*]Shift (single target) and Ctrl (checkered pattern) modifiers apply to gun-paint too
[*]Right-click the gun to switch between [b]Add Glow[/b] and [b]Remove Glow[/b] modes (vanilla on/off toggle, HUD label rebranded)
[*]Glow state persists across save/load and syncs in multiplayer
[*]Server toggle "Enable Glow Paint" disables the feature; when off, the gun reverts to vanilla can-accepting behavior
[/list]

[h3]Safe to Uninstall[/h3]
Saves written by v1.6.0+ open cleanly without this mod; glow lives in a side-car the vanilla loader ignores.

[h3]Settings[/h3]

All features are configurable via the mod settings panel.

[b]Client - Paintability[/b] (personal preference, each player sets independently):
[list]
[*][b]Make More Structures Paintable[/b] (default On): Paint structures the base game leaves unpaintable, currently the Steel Frame corner and side shapes
[/list]

[b]Client - Preferences[/b] (personal preference, each player sets independently):
[list]
[*][b]Paint Single Item By Default[/b] (default Off): Swap Shift behavior, single paint by default, hold Shift for network paint
[*][b]Invert Color Scroll Direction[/b] (default Off): Reverse the scroll wheel direction
[/list]

[b]Server - Consumables[/b] (the host's value controls gameplay for everyone):
[list]
[*][b]Unlimited Spray Paint Uses[/b] (default On): Infinite spray cans
[*][b]Suppress Spray Paint Pollution[/b] (default On): No pollutant gas when spraying
[/list]

[b]Server - Glow Paint[/b]:
[list]
[*][b]Enable Glow Paint[/b] (default On): The Spray Paint Gun adds glow to painted targets without changing color, and the gun no longer accepts spray cans. When off, the gun reverts to its vanilla behavior
[/list]

[b]Server - Network Painting[/b]:
[list]
[*][b]Enable Network Painting[/b] (default On): Paint entire networks at once
[*][b]Network Paint Pipes[/b] (default On): Include pipes in network painting
[*][b]Network Paint Cables[/b] (default On): Include cables in network painting
[*][b]Network Paint Chutes[/b] (default On): Include chutes in network painting
[*][b]Network Paint Walls[/b] (default On): Paint all same-type walls bounding the same room
[*][b]Network Paint Rails[/b] (default On): Paint every rail, junction, bypass, and dock on the same robotic arm assembly in one stroke
[*][b]Network Paint Large Structures[/b] (default On): Paint connected frames, girders, and other large structures in a 6-neighbor grid
[*][b]Network Paint Elevators[/b] (default On): Paint all shaft and level segments on one elevator (the carriage is painted separately)
[*][b]Network Paint Ladders[/b] (default On): Paint a whole ladder column in one stroke, including ladder end caps
[*][b]Network Paint Stairs[/b] (default On): Paint a whole staircase, both flights set side by side to widen it and flights run up or down to lengthen it
[*][b]Network Paint Stairwells[/b] (default On): Paint every adjacent stairwell, across all eight stairwell types and any orientation
[/list]

[h2]Compatibility[/h2]

[b]Requires:[/b]
[list]
[*][url=https://docs.bepinex.dev/]BepInEx[/url]
[*][url=https://github.com/StationeersLaunchPad/StationeersLaunchPad]StationeersLaunchPad[/url]
[/list]

[b]Incompatible with[/b] (detected at startup; the mod refuses to load if either is found):
[list]
[*][url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3163662298]Color Cycler[/url] by Elmotrix
[*][url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2876605527]Network Painter[/url] by Elmotrix
[/list]

[b]Redundant[/b] (disable if installed): [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3576112002]Infinite Spray Paint[/url] by Aspct, [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1761980496]Infinite Paint Mod[/url] by Dingo.

[b]All players[/b] (including dedicated servers) need the same BepInEx + StationeersLaunchPad + Spray Paint Plus setup; matching versions are enforced by the handshake.

[h2]Reporting Issues[/h2]
Found a bug? Please open an issue on [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/issues]GitHub[/url] with the mod name in the title. Steam comment notifications are unreliable, so GitHub is the way to make sure a report is seen.

[h2]Credits[/h2]
[list]
[*][b]Elmotrix[/b]: Created [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3163662298]Color Cycler[/url] and [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2876605527]Network Painter[/url]. The core ideas of scroll-to-cycle and paint-entire-networks are theirs.
[*][b]SubHobo[/b] (bls220): Contributed the initial multiplayer networking code to Color Cycler via [url=https://github.com/Elmotrix/ColorCyclerMod/pull/1]PR #1[/url].
[*][b]Aspct[/b]: Created [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3576112002]Infinite Spray Paint[/url].
[*][b]Dingo (DingoPD)[/b]: Created the original [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=1761980496]Infinite Paint Mod[/url].
[/list]

[url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/tree/master/Mods/SprayPaintPlus]Source Code on GitHub[/url]

[h2]License[/h2]
Licensed under the [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/blob/master/LICENSE]Apache License 2.0[/url]. Attribution required; see the LICENSE and NOTICE files at the repository root.</Description>
  <ChangeLog>
v1.10.0: Paint the Steel Frame corner and side variants
- NEW: The Steel Frame (Corner) and Steel Frame (Side) shapes now accept spray paint, like the other two shapes from the Steel Frames kit. The base game ships them without a paintable surface, so the spray can ignored them.
- NEW: Client setting "Make More Structures Paintable" (default On), under a new Client - Paintability group. More normally-unpaintable structures will be added in later versions.
- Painted frames also flood through Network Paint Large Structures like any other connected structure.
- Multiplayer-safe; no save-format changes.
- REQUIRES: All players on a server must run 1.10.0 (matching-version handshake).
  </ChangeLog>
  <WorkshopHandle>3702940349</WorkshopHandle>
  <Tags>
    <Tag>BepInEx</Tag>
    <Tag>StationeersLaunchPad</Tag>
    <Tag>paint</Tag>
    <Tag>multiplayer</Tag>
  </Tags>
  <InGameDescription><![CDATA[<size="30"><color=#ffa500>Spray Paint Plus</color></size>
<line-height=40%>Combines color cycling, network painting, glow paint, and infinite spray paint into one multiplayer-safe Stationeers mod.
Full multiplayer compatibility. Safe to remove from existing savegames.
<b>Features:</b>
- Scroll wheel cycles spray can colors
- Right-click a target with a can to copy its color; Ctrl+right-click picks the as-built kit color
- Infinite spray paint, no pollution (both configurable)
- One-stroke paint for pipe / cable / chute networks, rooms of same-type walls, connected large structures, robotic arm rail assemblies, elevators, ladder columns, staircases, and stairwell blocks
- Spray Paint Gun adds glow to painted targets (ammo-less, preserves color); right-click the gun to toggle Add Glow / Remove Glow mode
- Shift = single item, Ctrl = checkered pattern
- Full multiplayer with matching-version handshake
- Safe to uninstall: v1.6.0+ saves open cleanly without this mod
<b>Settings:</b> Server settings control gameplay for all players; client settings are personal.
<b>Requires:</b> BepInEx + StationeersLaunchPad. All players, including dedicated servers, need the same setup.
<b>Incompatible with:</b> Color Cycler, Network Painter (both by Elmotrix).
<b>Redundant</b> (disable if installed): Infinite Spray Paint by Aspct, Infinite Paint Mod by Dingo.
<b>Credits:</b> Elmotrix, SubHobo (bls220), Aspct, Dingo.</line-height>
]]></InGameDescription>
</ModMetadata>
