<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetadata xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Name>Power Transmitter Plus</Name>
  <ModID>net.powertransmitterplus</ModID>
  <Author>SixFive7</Author>
  <Version>1.1.3</Version>
  <Description>[h1]Power Transmitter Plus[/h1]

Adds a visible beam, scrolling pulses, a configurable distance cost, and new logic readouts to the Microwave Power Transmitter.

[h2]Features[/h2]

[h3]Visible Laser Beam[/h3]
A colored beam is drawn between a linked transmitter and receiver whenever the link is up and powered. The beam is at full brightness at all times while visible, so you can see at a glance which dishes are actually connected.

[h3]Scrolling Pulse Train[/h3]
Energy pulses scroll along the beam from transmitter to receiver. Stripe spacing is constant in world meters (same look on a 5m link or a 500m link). Scroll speed scales with power throughput, so a lightly-loaded link is clearly distinguishable from a heavily-loaded one at a glance.

[h3]Distance Cost[/h3]
Vanilla Stationeers caps microwave transmission capacity based on distance and hard-stops at 500m. This mod removes that cap entirely and replaces it with a source-draw overhead: the transmitter pulls more from its source cable network per watt delivered, proportional to link distance. Formula: for every watt delivered, the source pulls (1 + k * distance_km) watts. With the default k = 5:
[list]
[*]0 m: 1.0 watts drawn per watt delivered
[*]100 m: 1.5 watts drawn per watt delivered
[*]500 m: 3.5 watts drawn per watt delivered
[*]1 km: 6.0 watts drawn per watt delivered
[*]5 km: 26.0 watts drawn per watt delivered
[/list]
You can transmit any distance you like, but long-range transmission is paid for in waste heat at the source.

[h3]Logic Readouts[/h3]
Five read-only logic types are available on both the transmitter and the receiver, readable from configuration tablets and from IC10:
[list]
[*][b]MicrowaveSourceDraw[/b] (6571): watts pulled from the source cable network
[*][b]MicrowaveDestinationDraw[/b] (6572): watts delivered to the receiver's cable network
[*][b]MicrowaveTransmissionLoss[/b] (6573): source minus destination (watts lost to distance)
[*][b]MicrowaveEfficiency[/b] (6574): delivered / source as a 0..1 ratio
[*][b]MicrowaveLinkedPartner[/b] (6576): ReferenceId of the linked partner dish (0 when unlinked)
[/list]
The power readouts (6571-6574) return 0 when the link is down, the device is off, or no power is flowing. MicrowaveLinkedPartner returns 0 only when unlinked, regardless of power state.

[h3]Auto-Aim[/h3]
A writable logic type [b]MicrowaveAutoAimTarget[/b] (6575) on both transmitter and receiver. Write a Thing's ReferenceId and the dish slews to point at it via the built-in servo; the base game's link raycast decides when the pairing actually forms, so obstacles in the path still take priority. Writing 0 disables. Manually adjusting Horizontal or Vertical cancels auto-aim. This enables IC10 patterns like switching transmit target when remote batteries fill.

[h3]Settings[/h3]

All features are configurable via the mod settings panel.

[b]Client settings[/b] (visual preference, each player sets independently):
[list]
[*][b]Beam Width[/b] (default 0.1): Thickness of the beam in world meters
[*][b]Beam Color[/b] (default 000DFF): Hex RGB color. 000DFF is the vanilla cyan-blue
[*][b]Emission Intensity[/b] (default 10.0): HDR brightness multiplier on the beam color
[*][b]Stripe Wavelength[/b] (default 2.0): Distance in world meters between one pulse and the next
[*][b]Scroll Speed[/b] (default 25.0): Pulse scroll speed in world meters per second at full power (5 kW delivered). Scales with sqrt(intensity) so low loads still move visibly
[*][b]Trough Brightness[/b] (default 0.5): Beam brightness between pulses, 0..1. Regenerates on game restart
[/list]

[b]Server settings[/b] (the host's value controls gameplay and visuals for everyone):
[list]
[*][b]Cost Factor (k)[/b] (default 5.0): Per-kilometer overhead on transmitter source draw. k = 0 disables the overhead entirely; k = 10 doubles it compared to the default. Live-broadcast to all connected clients when changed
[/list]
In multiplayer, the host's beam visual settings (width, color, emission intensity, stripe wavelength, scroll speed) are always broadcast to all clients on connect and on change.

[h2]Compatibility[/h2]

[b]Requires:[/b]
[list]
[*][url=https://docs.bepinex.dev/]BepInEx[/url]
[*][url=https://github.com/StationeersLaunchPad/StationeersLaunchPad]StationeersLaunchPad[/url]
[/list]

[b]All players[/b] on a server must have Power Transmitter Plus installed. Matching mod versions are enforced during the connection handshake automatically.

[b]Dedicated servers[/b] need the same BepInEx + StationeersLaunchPad + PowerTransmitterPlus setup installed server-side. The distance-cost simulation runs server-authoritatively and the handshake rejects mixed installs.

[b]Custom logic type range[/b] 6571-6599 is reserved by this mod. Any other mod that registers a LogicType in that range will collide. The range sits well outside the vanilla enum (0-349) and the range used by Stationeers Logic Extended (1000-1830).

[h2]Reporting Issues[/h2]
If you run into a bug or something behaves unexpectedly, please open an issue on [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/issues]GitHub[/url]. Please include the mod name in the title so reports can be triaged. Steam comment notifications don't always come through, so GitHub is the reliable way to make sure a report is seen.

[h2]Credits[/h2]
[list]
[*][b]ThunderDuck[/b]: Created [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3625190467]Stationeers Logic Extended[/url], which pioneered the pattern for registering custom LogicType values. The injection approach used here (extending ProgrammableChip.AllConstants, Logicable.LogicTypes, and the enum-name lookup paths) is adapted from that work.
[/list]

[url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/tree/master/Mods/PowerTransmitterPlus]Source Code on GitHub[/url]

[h2]License[/h2]
Licensed under the [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/blob/master/LICENSE]Apache License 2.0[/url]. Attribution required; see the LICENSE and NOTICE files at the repository root.</Description>
  <ChangeLog>
v1.1.3: Screen syntax highlighting fix
- Fixed custom LogicType names rendering red on in-game computer and laptop screen previews

v1.1.2: Remove Shader Name config entry
- Removed the Shader Name config entry. The beam shader is now fixed to the built-in fallback chain (Legacy Shaders/Particles/Additive with three fallbacks).

v1.1.1: Patch release (Workshop preview images in build output)
- Added <WorkshopHandle> to About.xml and ensured Preview.png / thumb.png copy to the build output for the Workshop upload pipeline.

v1.1.0: Link-partner logic and host-broadcast beam visuals
- Added MicrowaveLinkedPartner (6576): read-only LogicType returning the ReferenceId of the currently linked partner dish on both transmitter and receiver
- Host beam visual settings (width, color, emission intensity, stripe wavelength, scroll speed) are now always synced to all clients in multiplayer

v1.0.0: Initial release
- Draws a visible laser beam between linked microwave transmitter and receiver dishes
- Scrolling energy pulses along the beam, speed proportional to power throughput
- Replaces vanilla distance-based capacity derate with a configurable source-draw overhead (k factor, server-authoritative)
- Adds MicrowaveSourceDraw / MicrowaveDestinationDraw / MicrowaveTransmissionLoss / MicrowaveEfficiency logic readouts on both transmitter and receiver (LogicType values 6571-6574)
- Writable MicrowaveAutoAimTarget (6575): IC10 can aim the dish at any Thing by ReferenceId
- IC10 name resolution for all five new LogicTypes
- Full multiplayer support with server-authoritative simulation and live config broadcast
  </ChangeLog>
  <WorkshopHandle>3707677512</WorkshopHandle>
  <Tags>
    <Tag>BepInEx</Tag>
    <Tag>StationeersLaunchPad</Tag>
    <Tag>power</Tag>
    <Tag>logic</Tag>
    <Tag>multiplayer</Tag>
    <Tag>StationeersPlus</Tag>
  </Tags>
  <InGameDescription><![CDATA[<size="30"><color=#00aaff>Power Transmitter Plus</color></size>
Adds a visible beam, scrolling pulses, a configurable distance cost, and new logic readouts to the Microwave Power Transmitter.

<b>Features:</b>
- Visible laser beam between linked transmitter and receiver dishes
- Scrolling energy pulses, speed scales with power throughput
- Replaces vanilla distance derate with a source-draw overhead (1 + k * distance_km watts drawn per watt delivered). Default k = 5. No more 500m hard cap.
- Five read-only logic readouts (tablet + IC10): MicrowaveSourceDraw (6571), MicrowaveDestinationDraw (6572), MicrowaveTransmissionLoss (6573), MicrowaveEfficiency (6574), MicrowaveLinkedPartner (6576)
- Writable MicrowaveAutoAimTarget (6575): write a Thing's ReferenceId to auto-aim the dish; write 0 to disable
- Full multiplayer support with server-authoritative simulation

<b>Settings:</b>
All features are configurable via the mod settings panel.
Server setting Cost Factor (k) controls gameplay for all players.
In multiplayer, the host's beam visual settings always override client-local config.

<b>Requirements:</b> BepInEx + StationeersLaunchPad

<b>Multiplayer:</b> All players must have this mod installed. Matching mod versions are enforced during the connection handshake automatically. Dedicated servers need the same setup installed server-side.
]]></InGameDescription>
</ModMetadata>
