<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetadata xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Name>Power Grid Plus</Name>
  <ModID>net.powergridplus</ModID>
  <Author>SixFive7</Author>
  <Version>0.1.0</Version>
  <Description>[h1]Power Grid Plus[/h1]

Reworks the Stationeers power simulation and turns the three cable tiers into three separate transmission voltages.

A pure-patch mod: no new craftable devices, no asset bundle. The simulation half is derived from Sukasa's Re-Volt (MIT); the three-tier voltage backbone is new. Full multiplayer compatibility. Safe to remove from existing savegames.

This is an early build. The reactive enforcement works; the build-time placement warnings, the transformer tier mapping, and the recipe cost change are still being wired up.

[h2]Features[/h2]

[h3]Reworked power simulation (from Re-Volt)[/h3]
[list]
[*]Electrical load is shared proportionally across every source on a network, and split proportionally across every load.
[*]Cables burn out gradually and probabilistically when overloaded, based on a short rolling average of throughput, instead of instantly. Fuses still blow instantly and always blow before a cable does.
[*]Recursive and looped power networks are allowed (the vanilla force-burn check is off by default; re-enable it in settings).
[*]Stationary batteries are charge- and discharge-rate limited, with an optional charge-efficiency setting, and expose their rate limits as logic values.
[*]Transformers no longer leak free power and charge their own quiescent draw upstream; they expose throughput as the Power Actual logic value.
[*]Area Power Controllers no longer leak a small amount of power or slowly drain their battery when nothing downstream is drawing.
[/list]
Re-Volt's circuit breakers and Load Center are not included; this is the pure-simulation subset.

[h3]Three-tier transmission voltages (new)[/h3]
[list]
[*]Super-heavy cable never burns out -- it is the long-haul backbone. Normal and heavy cable keep their ratings.
[*]Super-heavy cable costs twice as much to craft (configurable; 1.0 = vanilla). Recipe patching still in progress.
[*]The three cable tiers are three separate voltages. A cable network must be all one tier; joining two tiers burns the lower-tier cable at the junction and splits the network apart. The only legal bridge is a transformer.
[*]Electrical generators belong on heavy cable. A generator on a normal or super-heavy network produces no power. Step generation down through a transformer.
[/list]

[h3]Settings[/h3]
All settings are server-authoritative: in multiplayer the host's value controls gameplay for everyone. Highlights:
[list]
[*][b]Cable Burn Factor[/b] (default 1.0): scales the per-tick cable burn chance; 0.0 disables gradual burnout.
[*][b]Enable Unlimited Super-Heavy Cables[/b] (default true), [b]Super-Heavy Cable Cost Multiplier[/b] (default 2.0).
[*][b]Enable Voltage Tiers[/b] (default true), [b]Generators Require Heavy Cable[/b] (default true).
[*][b]Enable Battery Limits[/b] / [b]Max Battery Charge Rate[/b] / [b]Max Battery Discharge Rate[/b] / [b]Battery Charge Efficiency[/b].
[*][b]Enable Transformer Exploit Mitigation[/b], [b]Enable APC Power Fix[/b].
[/list]

[h2]Compatibility[/h2]

[b]Requires:[/b]
[list]
[*][url=https://docs.bepinex.dev/]BepInEx[/url]
[*][url=https://github.com/StationeersLaunchPad/StationeersLaunchPad]StationeersLaunchPad[/url]
[/list]

[b]All players[/b] on a server must have Power Grid Plus installed. Matching mod versions are enforced during the connection handshake automatically. [b]Dedicated servers[/b] need the same BepInEx + StationeersLaunchPad + Power Grid Plus setup installed server-side.

Re-Volt itself swaps the power tick the same way this mod does, so running both is not supported.

[h2]Reporting Issues[/h2]
If you run into a bug or something behaves unexpectedly, please open an issue on [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/issues]GitHub[/url]. Please include the mod name in the title so reports can be triaged. Steam comment notifications don't always come through, so GitHub is the reliable way to make sure a report is seen.

[h2]Credits[/h2]
[list]
[*]Built on the power-simulation work in [url=https://github.com/sukasa/revolt]Re-Volt[/url] by Sukasa, used under the MIT License. The Re-Volt-derived portions retain their MIT notice; see the repository NOTICE.
[/list]

[url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/tree/master/Mods/PowerGridPlus]Source Code on GitHub[/url]

[h2]License[/h2]
Licensed under the [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/blob/master/LICENSE]Apache License 2.0[/url]. Attribution required; see the LICENSE and NOTICE files at the repository root.</Description>
  <ChangeLog>
v0.1.0: First build (work in progress)
- Reworked cable-network power tick from Re-Volt: proportional load sharing, gradual probabilistic cable burnout on a rolling throughput average, NaN-power guard.
- Stationary battery charge/discharge-rate limits + optional charge efficiency + rate-limit logic values.
- Transformer free-power exploit fix + quiescent-draw restore + Power Actual logic value.
- Area Power Controller power-leak / idle-drain fix.
- Recursive and looped networks allowed by default.
- New: super-heavy cable never burns; the three cable tiers are separate transmission voltages (mixing them burns the boundary cable and splits the network); generators only produce power on heavy cable.
- Not finished yet: build-time placement warnings, small/medium/large transformer tier mapping, super-heavy cable coil recipe cost change.
  </ChangeLog>
  <WorkshopHandle>0</WorkshopHandle>
  <Tags>
    <Tag>BepInEx</Tag>
    <Tag>StationeersLaunchPad</Tag>
    <Tag>power</Tag>
    <Tag>multiplayer</Tag>
    <Tag>StationeersPlus</Tag>
  </Tags>
  <InGameDescription><![CDATA[<size="30"><color=#ffa500>Power Grid Plus</color></size>
<line-height=40%>Reworks the Stationeers power simulation and turns the three cable tiers into three separate transmission voltages.
A pure-patch mod (no new prefabs). Simulation half derived from Re-Volt (MIT). Full multiplayer compatibility. Safe to remove from existing savegames. Early build -- some pieces still in progress.
<b>From Re-Volt:</b>
- Proportional load sharing across sources and loads.
- Gradual probabilistic cable burnout on a rolling throughput average; fuses still blow first.
- Recursive/looped networks allowed; battery charge/discharge limits + logic values; transformer exploit fix + Power Actual logic value; APC power-leak fix.
<b>New:</b>
- Super-heavy cable never burns; it is the long-haul backbone.
- The three cable tiers are separate voltages; mixing them burns the boundary cable. Bridge tiers with a transformer.
- Generators only produce power on heavy cable.
<b>Settings:</b> Server-authoritative; the host's values control gameplay for everyone.
<b>Requires:</b> BepInEx + StationeersLaunchPad. All players, including dedicated servers, need the same setup.
</line-height>
]]></InGameDescription>
</ModMetadata>
