<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetadata xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Name>Power Grid Plus</Name>
  <ModID>net.powergridplus</ModID>
  <Author>SixFive7</Author>
  <Version>0.2.0</Version>
  <Description>[h1]Power Grid Plus[/h1]

Reworks Stationeers wired power: an atomic power tick with priority-based transformer dispatch, automatic shedding and overload lockouts, loop and producer-isolation faults with on-device countdowns, elastic battery allocation, three cable tiers as separate transmission voltages, logic-transparent transformer / battery / dish bridges, and deterministic multiplayer cable-network ids.

A pure-patch mod: no new devices, no asset bundle. Parts derive from Sukasa's Re-Volt (MIT). Multiplayer-compatible; safe to remove from a save. Early build. The power simulation is fully mod-owned and the vanilla power flow never runs, so its races, billing leaks, and partial-power brownouts are gone. A machine is either fully powered or its network is cleanly dark with a visible fault.

[h2]Features[/h2]

[h3]Faults: visible lockouts instead of silent misbehaviour[/h3]
[list]
[*][b]Shedding[/b] (orange flash): the input network cannot cover the device; the lowest Priority sheds first and its subnet goes dark for 60 seconds.
[*][b]Overloaded[/b] (red flash): delivering everything Setting allows (or a battery at its full rate) while demand stays unmet; the bottleneck trips.
[*][b]Cycle Fault[/b] (red flash): every member of a power loop faults and contributes 0, dissolving the loop without a burn.
[*][b]Variable Voltage Fault[/b] (red flash): a producer may only share a network with other producers and transformers; strict: batteries and other bridges count too, and a transformer exempts nothing.
[*]A machine's own demand spike can never reboot it: Powered is decided from the network's state, so a printer starting a job keeps running. Powered and on/off are always independent: a switched-off device on a live network reads Power=1; read On for the switch.
[*]Hover text names the cause with a live countdown; toggling off clears instantly. A healthy idle bridge stays powered.
[/list]

[h3]Elastic storage[/h3]
[list]
[*]Batteries, APC cells, and rocket power umbilicals charge only from surplus and discharge only to fill a shortfall, sharing proportionally. No battery ping-pong.
[*]Charging spans the whole grid: surplus routes through transformers and dish pairs to batteries behind them, never displacing running machines; a short charge request is trimmed, never a fault.
[*]Per-prefab charge / discharge rate caps (batteries, APC cell, umbilical), each also capped by the cable tier.
[*]MaxChargeSpeed / MaxDischargeSpeed and live ChargeSpeed / DischargeSpeed logic values on every storage device; Import Quantity / Export Quantity are removed.
[*]Transformers never leak free power; APCs never leak or drain their cell while idle.
[/list]

[h3]Three-tier transmission voltages (new)[/h3]
[list]
[*]The three cable tiers are separate voltages: a network must be all one tier, a wrong-tier cable burns on the next powered tick (an idle network destroys nothing), and transformers / APCs are the bridges.
[*]Devices belong on their tier: generators and stationary batteries on heavy; high-draw machines (configurable) on heavy or normal; super-heavy is cables-and-transformers only; the rest on normal. A misplaced device burns the adjacent cable when power flows, never the device itself.
[*]Per-tier cable Watts caps (normal 5000, heavy 100000, super-heavy 0 = unlimited), runtime-enforced; cables in the save are never modified. Super-heavy cable costs 2x to craft (configurable).
[*]Only direct generator overflow burns cables (a deterministic 10 s sustained-average rule); transformer or battery overflow trips the upstream devices into Overloaded instead.
[*]A wrong-tier cable shows a red "Wrong voltage" ghost at the cursor; device placement is never blocked. Burned cables explain why on hover, and the reason survives save / load.
[/list]

[h3]Transformer priority and dispatch (new)[/h3]
[list]
[*]Setting is the vanilla throughput cap again (IC10 reads and writes it as in the base game); new transformers start at full throughput, saved worlds keep theirs.
[*]The in-world knob and the Labeller set [b]Priority[/b] instead (default 100, step 10 per click or 1 with Alt). Priority decides who sheds first, per input network, and shedding is leaf-first: mid-chain bridges forward a deficit downstream.
[*]New writable [b]Priority[/b] + read-only [b]Shedding[/b] / [b]Overloaded[/b] / [b]CycleFault[/b] logic values; Priority saves with the world and syncs in multiplayer.
[*]Transmitter / receiver dish pairs join dispatch like transformers, using whichever distance-cost model is active.
[/list]

[h3]Logic passthrough (new)[/h3]
[list]
[*]Bridging devices (transformers, batteries, APCs, linked dish pairs, docked umbilicals) can be made logic-transparent: a reader sees through the bridge, and a whole chain of bridges, with no extra data cable.
[*]A writable LogicPassthroughMode controls it per device, saved with the world; passthrough support is always on. Six Passthrough Default settings seed a device whose mode was never set (transparent except non-small transformers); a stored mode wins once set; the APC (no logic port) is config-seeded only.
[/list]

[h3]Diagnostics (new)[/h3]
[list]
[*]A conservation check audits the allocator every tick: inflow must match outflow on every network, and every bridge must bill exactly what it passes on plus its own draw; a violation means a mod bug.
[*]Stale wireless transfer debts in old saves are zeroed on load; delivery audits verify every store is credited exactly its grant.
[*]Unrecognised two-port power devices from other mods are listed once at load.
[/list]

[h3]Settings[/h3]
All settings are server-authoritative: the host's value applies for everyone. Highlights:
[list]
[*]Per-tier cable Watts caps + super-heavy craft cost, per-prefab battery / APC / umbilical charge / discharge rates, [b]Battery Charge Efficiency[/b] (default 1.5: grid energy drawn per unit stored), an extra heavy-cable device list for modded machines.
[*]The six [b]Passthrough Default[/b] seeds for devices whose mode was never set, the battery / transformer [b]Logic Additions[/b] toggles, and the [b]Emergency Light[/b] master + prefab list.
[*]Always on (no toggle): voltage tiers, cycle faults, producer isolation, deterministic cable burns, battery / umbilical rate limits, transformer shedding and overload protection, the conservation audit, Powered decoupled from on/off, logic passthrough support, the transformer and APC power fixes, device Powered ownership, idle-bridge powered presentation, wireless ledger cleanup.
[/list]

[h2]Compatibility[/h2]

[b]Requires:[/b]
[list]
[*][url=https://docs.bepinex.dev/]BepInEx[/url]
[*][url=https://github.com/StationeersLaunchPad/StationeersLaunchPad]StationeersLaunchPad[/url]
[/list]

[b]All players[/b] and the dedicated server must run Power Grid Plus; matching versions are enforced in the connection handshake.

Re-Volt also swaps the power tick, so running both is not supported. Power Transmitter Plus is fully compatible: 1.9.0+ hands wireless billing to Power Grid Plus through a load-time handshake; beam visuals, links, and capacity settings stay there.

[h2]Reporting Issues[/h2]
Please report bugs as issues on [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/issues]GitHub[/url], with the mod name in the title. Steam comment notifications don't always come through, so GitHub is the reliable channel.

[h2]Credits[/h2]
[list]
[*]Built on the power-simulation work in [url=https://github.com/sukasa/revolt]Re-Volt[/url] by Sukasa (MIT License; the derived portions retain their notice, see the repository NOTICE).
[/list]

[url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/tree/master/Mods/PowerGridPlus]Source Code on GitHub[/url]

[h2]License[/h2]
Licensed under the [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/blob/master/LICENSE]Apache License 2.0[/url]. Attribution required; see the LICENSE and NOTICE files at the repository root.</Description>
  <ChangeLog>
v0.2.0: Atomic power tick and the fault system (work in progress)
- The power simulation is fully mod-owned: one per-tick snapshot reads the whole grid exactly once, the global allocator solves every network at once, and a write-back applies the result (energy, storage, Powered flags, network readouts, fuses, cable burns). The vanilla per-network power flow no longer runs, so its mid-tick races, billing leaks, and partial-power brownouts are gone: a machine is either fully powered or its network is cleanly dark with a visible fault.
- Load shedding is leaf-first: only bridges feeding end-of-chain networks with unmet demand shed, lowest Priority first; mid-chain hops forward the deficit downstream instead of decapitating a whole supply chain.
- Four 60-second fault lockouts with on-device feedback: Shedding (orange flash; the input network cannot cover the device, lowest Priority sheds first), Overloaded (red; at the cap with demand still unmet), Cycle Fault (red; every loop member faults and the loop dissolves without a burn), and Variable Voltage Fault (red; an unprotected producer stops generating). Hover text names the cause with a live countdown; toggling off clears instantly.
- Producer isolation is always on and strict: producers (solar, wind, generators, RTG, turbine, dynamic generator dock) may only share a cable network with other producers and transformers. Anything else on the network faults the producers (batteries and other bridging devices included); a transformer does not exempt the rest. Unrecognised modded producers fall back to burning the cable next to the violating device.
- Elastic storage: batteries, APC cells, and rocket power umbilicals charge only from surplus and discharge only to fill a shortfall, sharing proportionally. New read-only logic values MaxChargeSpeed, MaxDischargeSpeed, ChargeSpeed, and DischargeSpeed on all storage devices; the earlier Import Quantity / Export Quantity exposure on batteries is removed (breaking change).
- Battery Charge Efficiency is now a charge cost: grid energy drawn per unit stored, default 1.5 (a battery stores two thirds of what it draws; values below 1.0 count as 1.0). Post-loss trickles below 500 W store in full. The loss is destroyed for now; a heat conversion is planned.
- Transformer Setting is vanilla again: IC10 reads and writes the live throughput cap (the earlier Setting-to-Priority write redirect is removed); new transformers start at full throughput, saved worlds keep their Settings, and Setting 0 means deliberately off (logged at load). The knob and the Labeller set Priority (no upper cap); dispatch is per input network by Priority.
- Cable Watts caps are configurable per tier (normal 5000, heavy 100000, super-heavy unlimited; 0 = unlimited) and enforced at runtime only; cables in the save are never modified, so removing the mod restores vanilla ratings.
- Only direct generator overflow burns cables; transformer or battery overflow trips the upstream devices into Overloaded instead. Burned-cable reasons survive save and load.
- Power transmitter / receiver pairs participate in dispatch as transformer-like devices, using whichever distance-loss model is active (vanilla or PowerTransmitterPlus).
- Rocket power umbilical rate caps and logic values (charge / discharge rate settings; always on).
- Multiplayer fault sync rebuilt as per-tick full snapshots with a join handshake, so clients always show the correct flash and countdown, self-healing after packet loss.
- Emergency lights: the battery wall-light emergency behaviour applies to a configurable prefab list (default StructureWallLightBattery).
- Logic passthrough support is always on; a device bridges only while its LogicPassthroughMode is 1. Six new Passthrough Default settings seed a device whose mode was never set (newly built, or an existing save first running the mod); a stored mode wins once set. Defaults are transparent except non-small transformers; the APC (no logic port) is config-seeded only.
- Removed settings: Enable Voltage Tiers, Enable Recursive Network Limits, Enable Unlimited Super-Heavy Cables, Enable Transformer Exploit Mitigation, Enable APC Power Fix, Enable Battery Limits, Enable Transformer Shedding, and the per-family logic passthrough masters (all now always on; the super-heavy toggle became the 0 = unlimited cap; orphaned entries are ignored). New settings: the three per-tier cable caps, APC Battery Discharge Rate, the two Rocket Umbilical rate settings, the six per-family Passthrough Default seeds, and Emergency Light Prefabs.
- Devices no longer power-cycle on their own demand spikes: the mod decides every device's Powered flag from its network's state (live, shed, overloaded, or dead), so a printer starting a job cannot reboot itself and cancel the print. Either the subnet carries the load, or it goes dark as a unit for 60 seconds.
- Powered and the on/off switch are now independent (no toggle): a switched-off device on a live network reads Power=1 in IC10 and draws nothing. Read On for the switch state.
- Every device's demand and output is read exactly once per tick into the grid snapshot, so a mid-tick change can never tear the solve; the fabricator-family work accumulators drain on the thread that owns them, and unfunded work on a dark network freezes and bills in full on revival.

v0.1.0: First build (work in progress)
- Reworked cable-network power tick from Re-Volt: proportional load sharing, gradual probabilistic cable burnout on a rolling throughput average, NaN-power guard.
- Stationary battery charge/discharge-rate limits, optional charge efficiency, and rate-limit logic values.
- Transformer free-power exploit fix, quiescent-draw restore, and Power Actual logic value.
- Area Power Controller power-leak / idle-drain fix.
- Recursive and looped networks allowed by default.
- Super-heavy cable never burns; the three cable tiers are separate transmission voltages (mixing them burns the lower-tier boundary cable and splits the network); devices belong on their tier (generators and batteries on heavy, high-draw machines on heavy or normal, super-heavy is cables-and-transformers only, everything else on normal) and a device on the wrong tier gets no power; super-heavy cable coil costs 2x to craft (configurable via the multiplier).
- Reactive tier enforcement: a wrong-tier cable burns on the next power tick if the network has actual power flow (an idle or off network destroys nothing). Wrong-tier cable placement is blocked at the cursor with a "Wrong voltage" tooltip; device placement is never blocked. Burned cables explain why they burned in their hover tooltip.
- Logic passthrough: a writable LogicPassthroughMode logic value makes power-network bridging devices logic-transparent, so a logic reader sees devices on the far side, transitively across a whole chain of bridges (cycle-safe). Covers transformers, stationary batteries, linked power transmitter and receiver dishes, and Area Power Controllers. Per-device mode is server-authoritative, persists across save and load, and each device family has its own master server toggle.
- Transformer priority and load shedding: transformer throughput is hardcoded at the per-prefab OutputMaximum rating; the knob now sets a writable Priority value (default 100, step 10 per click or 1 with Alt). Allocation on a shared input network is strictly by Priority; a transformer that cannot get its full share sheds for 10 seconds (contributes 0, orange pulse, hover explains), then auto-clears. New writable Priority and read-only Shedding logic values; Setting writes redirect to Priority so legacy IC10 scripts keep working. Priority saves with the world and syncs in multiplayer. Master toggle Enable Transformer Shedding (default on).
- Deterministic network merge: when cable or structure networks merge, the survivor is chosen by lowest reference id so the host and all clients agree on the same network id (a multiplayer correctness fix).
  </ChangeLog>
  <WorkshopHandle>0</WorkshopHandle>
  <Tags>
    <Tag>BepInEx</Tag>
    <Tag>StationeersLaunchPad</Tag>
    <Tag>power</Tag>
    <Tag>multiplayer</Tag>
    <Tag>StationeersPlus</Tag>
  </Tags>
  <InGameDescription><![CDATA[<size="30"><color=#ffa500>Power Grid Plus</color></size>
<line-height=40%>Reworks Stationeers wired power: an atomic power tick with priority-based transformer dispatch, shedding and overload lockouts, loop and producer-isolation faults with on-device countdowns, elastic battery allocation, three cable tiers as separate voltages, logic-transparent bridges, and deterministic multiplayer network ids.
A pure-patch mod (no new prefabs). Multiplayer-compatible. Early build.
<b>Faults:</b>
- Shedding (orange flash), Overloaded / Cycle Fault / Variable Voltage Fault (red flash). 60 s lockouts, hover shows the cause with a live countdown, toggling off clears instantly.
- Producers (solar, wind, generators) may only share a network with producers and transformers.
<b>Dispatch:</b> Setting is the vanilla throughput cap; the knob and Labeller set Priority. Lowest priority sheds first per input network. Loops fault their devices instead of burning cables.
<b>Storage:</b> batteries / APCs / umbilicals charge only from surplus, discharge only to fill shortfalls. MaxChargeSpeed / MaxDischargeSpeed / ChargeSpeed / DischargeSpeed logic values.
<b>Tiers:</b> three cable tiers are separate voltages; configurable Watts caps, runtime-enforced (saves untouched). Only generator overflow burns cables.
<b>Requires:</b> BepInEx + StationeersLaunchPad.
</line-height>
]]></InGameDescription>
</ModMetadata>
