<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetadata xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Name>Power Grid Plus</Name>
  <ModID>net.powergridplus</ModID>
  <Author>SixFive7</Author>
  <Version>0.2.0</Version>
  <Description>[h1]Power Grid Plus[/h1]

Reworks Stationeers wired power: an atomic power tick with priority-based transformer dispatch, automatic shedding and overload lockouts, loop and producer-isolation faults with on-device countdowns, elastic battery allocation, three cable tiers as separate transmission voltages, logic-transparent transformer / battery / dish bridges, and deterministic multiplayer cable-network ids.

A pure-patch mod: no new craftable devices, no asset bundle. Parts of the simulation are derived from Sukasa's Re-Volt (MIT). Full multiplayer compatibility. Safe to remove from existing savegames: cable ratings are enforced at runtime and never written into the save.

This is an early build. The inner per-network simulation is the unmodified vanilla PowerTick; Power Grid Plus decides faults and allocations globally each tick and applies them the same tick, keeping vanilla partial power as the safety net for anything unclassified.

[h2]Features[/h2]

[h3]Faults: visible lockouts instead of silent misbehaviour[/h3]
[list]
[*][b]Shedding[/b] (orange flash): the input network cannot cover the device. Siblings compete by Priority; the lowest sheds first and its subnet goes dark cleanly for 60 seconds instead of flickering.
[*][b]Overloaded[/b] (red flash): delivering everything Setting allows (or a battery at its full rate) while demand stays unmet. The bottleneck trips, so you know what to upgrade or split.
[*][b]Cycle Fault[/b] (red flash): the device closes a power loop. Every loop member faults and contributes 0, dissolving the loop. No cable is burned for loops.
[*][b]Variable Voltage Fault[/b] (red flash): a producer (solar, wind, generator, RTG) wired to consumers without a transformer stops generating. Producers may only share a network with producers and transformers.
[*]Hover text names the cause with a live countdown. Toggling the device off clears the fault instantly; toggling back on re-evaluates.
[/list]

[h3]Elastic storage[/h3]
[list]
[*]Batteries, APC cells, and rocket power umbilicals charge only from surplus and discharge only to fill a shortfall, sharing proportionally among competitors. No battery ping-pong.
[*]Per-prefab charge / discharge rate caps, each also capped by the cable tier.
[*]Read-only MaxChargeSpeed / MaxDischargeSpeed (configured caps) and ChargeSpeed / DischargeSpeed (live allocated rates) on every storage device. The earlier Import Quantity / Export Quantity exposure on batteries is removed.
[*]Transformers no longer leak free power; APCs no longer leak power or drain their cell while idle.
[/list]

[h3]Three-tier transmission voltages (new)[/h3]
[list]
[*]Cable Watts caps are configurable per tier (normal 5000, heavy 100000, super-heavy unlimited by default; 0 = unlimited) and enforced at runtime only -- cables in the save are never modified.
[*]Only direct generator overflow burns cables. Transformer or battery overflow trips the upstream devices into Overloaded instead; the cable survives and the fault tells you what to fix.
[*]Super-heavy cable costs twice as much to craft (configurable via the multiplier; 1.0 = vanilla).
[*]The three cable tiers are three separate voltages. A cable network must be all one tier; a wrong-tier cable burns on the next powered tick (an idle network destroys nothing). The only legal bridge between tiers is a transformer or an APC.
[*]Devices belong on the right tier: generators and stationary batteries on heavy, high-draw machines (the furnaces, Centrifuge, Recycler, and friends, plus any you add in the config) on heavy or normal, super-heavy is cables-and-transformers only, everything else on normal. A misplaced device burns the cable next to it when power flows (never the device itself). Transformers, APCs and wireless power devices are exempt.
[*]Placement UX: placing a wrong-tier cable next to an existing device or network shows a red ghost with a "Wrong voltage" tooltip. Device placement is never blocked at the cursor.
[*]Burned cables explain why in their hover tooltip ("Burned: overloaded", "Burned: wrong voltage"), and the reason survives save / load.
[/list]

[h3]Transformer priority and dispatch (new)[/h3]
[list]
[*]The vanilla Setting value is the throughput cap again: IC10 reads and writes it exactly as in the base game. New transformers start at full throughput; saved worlds keep their saved Settings.
[*]The in-world knob and the Labeller set [b]Priority[/b] instead (non-negative integer, no upper cap, default 100, step 10 per click or 1 with Alt). Priority decides who sheds first; comparisons are local to each input network.
[*]New writable [b]Priority[/b] + read-only [b]Shedding[/b] / [b]Overloaded[/b] / [b]CycleFault[/b] logic values.
[*]Priority saves with the world and rides the multiplayer join handshake. Master toggles for shedding and overload protection restore the vanilla behaviours when off.
[*]Power transmitter / receiver dish pairs participate in dispatch like transformers, using whichever distance-loss model is active.
[/list]

[h3]Logic passthrough (new)[/h3]
[list]
[*]Bridging devices (transformers, batteries, APCs, linked dish pairs) can be made logic-transparent: a reader sees through the bridge, and through a whole chain of bridges, with no extra data cable. Looped layouts are fine.
[*]A writable LogicPassthroughMode logic value controls it per device (1 = transparent, 0 = vanilla); defaults to transparent for batteries, dishes and the small transformer. Saved with the world. Per-family server master toggles.
[/list]

[h3]Settings[/h3]
All settings are server-authoritative: in multiplayer the host's value controls gameplay for everyone. Highlights:
[list]
[*][b]Normal / Heavy / Super Heavy Cable Max Watts[/b] (5000 / 100000 / 0; 0 = unlimited), [b]Super-Heavy Cable Cost Multiplier[/b] (2.0).
[*][b]Extra Heavy-Cable Devices[/b] (a comma-separated PrefabName list for modded high-draw machines).
[*]Per-prefab battery charge / discharge caps, [b]Battery Charge Efficiency[/b], APC and Rocket Umbilical charge / discharge rates.
[*][b]Enable Transformer Shedding[/b] and [b]Enable Transformer Overload Protection[/b] (both default true).
[*][b]Enable Transformer / Battery / Power Transmitter / APC Logic Passthrough[/b] (all default true).
[*][b]Emergency Light[/b] master toggle + a configurable prefab list for battery wall lights acting as emergency backup lights.
[*]Voltage tiers, cycle faults, and producer isolation are always on (no toggle); they are the core of the redesigned grid.
[/list]

[h2]Compatibility[/h2]

[b]Requires:[/b]
[list]
[*][url=https://docs.bepinex.dev/]BepInEx[/url]
[*][url=https://github.com/StationeersLaunchPad/StationeersLaunchPad]StationeersLaunchPad[/url]
[/list]

[b]All players[/b] on a server must have Power Grid Plus installed; matching versions are enforced in the connection handshake. [b]Dedicated servers[/b] need the same setup server-side.

Re-Volt itself swaps the power tick the same way this mod does, so running both is not supported.

[h2]Reporting Issues[/h2]
If you run into a bug or something behaves unexpectedly, please open an issue on [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/issues]GitHub[/url]. Please include the mod name in the title so reports can be triaged. Steam comment notifications don't always come through, so GitHub is the reliable way to make sure a report is seen.

[h2]Credits[/h2]
[list]
[*]Built on the power-simulation work in [url=https://github.com/sukasa/revolt]Re-Volt[/url] by Sukasa, used under the MIT License. The Re-Volt-derived portions retain their MIT notice; see the repository NOTICE.
[/list]

[url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/tree/master/Mods/PowerGridPlus]Source Code on GitHub[/url]

[h2]License[/h2]
Licensed under the [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/blob/master/LICENSE]Apache License 2.0[/url]. Attribution required; see the LICENSE and NOTICE files at the repository root.</Description>
  <ChangeLog>
v0.2.0: Atomic power tick and the fault system (work in progress)
- Atomic five-phase power tick: observe every network, decide every fault and allocation globally, then run the vanilla per-network power flow with those decisions in effect. Decisions apply in the same tick; the inner simulation is the unmodified vanilla PowerTick, and vanilla partial-power scaling stays as the safety net for unclassified devices.
- Four 60-second fault lockouts with on-device feedback: Shedding (orange flash; input network cannot cover the device, lowest Priority sheds first), Overloaded (red; delivering at the Setting cap or full battery discharge with demand still unmet), Cycle Fault (red; the device closes a power loop, every loop member faults and the loop dissolves without burning a cable), and Variable Voltage Fault (red; a producer wired to consumers without a transformer stops generating). Hover text names the cause with a live countdown; toggling the device off clears the fault instantly.
- Producer isolation is always on: producers (solar, wind, generators, RTG, turbine, dynamic generator dock) may only share a network with other producers and transformers. Unrecognised modded producers fall back to burning the cable next to the violating consumer.
- Elastic storage: batteries, APC cells, and rocket power umbilicals charge only from surplus and discharge only to fill a shortfall, with proportional sharing among competitors. New read-only logic values MaxChargeSpeed, MaxDischargeSpeed, ChargeSpeed, and DischargeSpeed on all storage devices; the earlier Import Quantity / Export Quantity exposure on batteries is removed (breaking change for scripts that read them).
- Transformer Setting is vanilla again: IC10 reads and writes the live throughput cap (the earlier redirect of Setting writes to Priority is removed); new transformers start at full throughput, saved worlds keep their saved Settings, and a Setting of 0 means deliberately off (logged at load). The knob and the Labeller set Priority (no upper cap). Dispatch is per input network by Priority.
- Cable Watts caps are configurable per tier (normal 5000, heavy 100000 matching vanilla, super-heavy unlimited; 0 = unlimited) and enforced at runtime only; cables in the save are never modified, so removing the mod restores vanilla ratings.
- Only direct generator overflow burns cables; transformer or battery overflow trips the upstream devices into Overloaded instead. Burned-cable reasons now survive save and load (side-car).
- Power transmitter / receiver pairs participate in dispatch as transformer-like devices, using whichever distance-loss model is active (vanilla curve or PowerTransmitterPlus).
- Rocket power umbilical rate caps and logic values (master toggle plus charge / discharge rate settings).
- Multiplayer fault sync rebuilt as per-tick full snapshots with a join handshake, so clients always show the correct flash and countdown, self-healing after packet loss.
- Emergency-light target list: the battery wall-light emergency behaviour now applies to a configurable prefab list (default StructureWallLightBattery).
- Removed settings: Enable Voltage Tiers, Enable Recursive Network Limits, Enable Unlimited Super-Heavy Cables (voltage tiers and loop handling are always on; the super-heavy toggle became the 0 = unlimited cap). New settings: the three per-tier cable caps, APC Battery Discharge Rate, the three Rocket Umbilical entries, Enable Transformer Overload Protection, and Emergency Light Prefabs.

v0.1.0: First build (work in progress)
- Reworked cable-network power tick from Re-Volt: proportional load sharing, gradual probabilistic cable burnout on a rolling throughput average, NaN-power guard.
- Stationary battery charge/discharge-rate limits, optional charge efficiency, and rate-limit logic values.
- Transformer free-power exploit fix, quiescent-draw restore, and Power Actual logic value.
- Area Power Controller power-leak / idle-drain fix.
- Recursive and looped networks allowed by default.
- Super-heavy cable never burns; the three cable tiers are separate transmission voltages (mixing them burns the lower-tier boundary cable and splits the network); devices belong on their tier (generators and batteries on heavy, high-draw machines on heavy or normal, super-heavy is cables-and-transformers only, everything else on normal) and a device on the wrong tier gets no power; super-heavy cable coil costs 2x to craft (configurable via the multiplier).
- Reactive tier enforcement: a wrong-tier cable burns on the next power tick if the network has actual power flow (an idle or off network destroys nothing). Wrong-tier cable placement is blocked at the cursor with a "Wrong voltage" tooltip; device placement is never blocked. Burned cables explain why they burned in their hover tooltip.
- Logic passthrough: a writable LogicPassthroughMode logic value (set via IC10 or a logic writer) makes power-network bridging devices logic-transparent, so a logic reader sees devices on the far side, transitively across a whole chain of bridged devices (cycle-safe, so looped networks are fine). Covers transformers, stationary batteries, linked power transmitter and receiver dishes, and Area Power Controllers. The per-device mode is server-authoritative, persists across save and load, and each device family has its own master server toggle.
- Transformer priority and load shedding: transformer throughput is hardcoded at the per-prefab OutputMaximum rating; the knob now sets a writable Priority value (default 100, step 10 per click or 1 with Alt). When transformers compete on the same input network, allocation is strictly by Priority: highest gets first dibs, leftover goes to the next priority. A transformer that cannot get its full share from the input network sheds for 10 seconds (contributes 0, on/off button pulses orange, hover shows "Shedding: insufficient upstream supply"); auto-clears after the hold. Two-tick tolerance prevents single-frame spikes from tripping a lockout. New writable Priority and read-only Shedding logic values; Setting writes are transparently redirected to Priority so legacy IC10 scripts keep working. Per-transformer Priority is saved with the world and synced across multiplayer in the join handshake. Server master toggle Enable Transformer Shedding (default on) restores vanilla behaviour when off.
- Deterministic network merge: when cable or structure networks merge, the survivor is chosen by lowest reference id so the host and all clients agree on the same network id (a multiplayer correctness fix).
  </ChangeLog>
  <WorkshopHandle>0</WorkshopHandle>
  <Tags>
    <Tag>BepInEx</Tag>
    <Tag>StationeersLaunchPad</Tag>
    <Tag>power</Tag>
    <Tag>multiplayer</Tag>
    <Tag>StationeersPlus</Tag>
  </Tags>
  <InGameDescription><![CDATA[<size="30"><color=#ffa500>Power Grid Plus</color></size>
<line-height=40%>Reworks Stationeers wired power: an atomic power tick with priority-based transformer dispatch, shedding and overload lockouts, loop and producer-isolation faults with on-device countdowns, elastic battery allocation, three cable tiers as separate voltages, logic-transparent bridges, and deterministic multiplayer network ids.
A pure-patch mod (no new prefabs). Multiplayer-compatible. Early build.
<b>Faults:</b>
- Shedding (orange flash), Overloaded / Cycle Fault / Variable Voltage Fault (red flash). 60 s lockouts, hover shows the cause with a live countdown, toggling off clears instantly.
- Producers (solar, wind, generators) may only share a network with producers and transformers.
<b>Dispatch:</b> Setting is the vanilla throughput cap; the knob and Labeller set Priority. Lowest priority sheds first per input network. Loops fault their devices instead of burning cables.
<b>Storage:</b> batteries / APCs / umbilicals charge only from surplus, discharge only to fill shortfalls. MaxChargeSpeed / MaxDischargeSpeed / ChargeSpeed / DischargeSpeed logic values.
<b>Tiers:</b> three cable tiers are separate voltages; configurable Watts caps, runtime-enforced (saves untouched). Only generator overflow burns cables.
<b>Requires:</b> BepInEx + StationeersLaunchPad.
</line-height>
]]></InGameDescription>
</ModMetadata>
