<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetadata xmlns:xsd="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance">
  <Name>Equipment Plus</Name>
  <ModID>net.equipmentplus</ModID>
  <Author>SixFive7</Author>
  <Version>1.0.0</Version>
  <Description>[h1]Equipment Plus[/h1]

Adds dynamic multi-slot sensor lenses and advanced tablets to Stationeers, with multiplayer-safe configuration cartridge enhancements.

Full multiplayer compatibility. Safe to remove from existing savegames.

Slots appear as you fill them and disappear as you empty them. The UI always shows exactly one empty slot, never a wall of boxes.

[h2]Features[/h2]

Supported items:
[list]
[*][b]Sensor Lenses[/b]: hold multiple sensor chips (Ore, Meson, Celestial, and any mod-added chips)
[*][b]Advanced Tablet[/b]: hold multiple cartridges (all vanilla + mod-added cartridges)
[/list]

[list]
[*]Dynamic slot growth: insert a chip/cartridge, a new empty slot appears
[*]Dynamic slot shrink: remove items, excess empty slots disappear
[*]Configuration Cartridge enhancements: scroll to select a line, left-click to copy read-only values or edit writable values (multiplayer-safe)
[*]Logic slot display: appends per-slot logic values to the Config Cartridge screen (writable slots in grey, read-only in green), absorbing Slot Configuration Cartridge (Workshop 3578912665)
[*]No config needed, it just works
[*]Full multiplayer support
[/list]

[h2]Scroll-Modifier Bindings[/h2]
Modifier+scroll layers equipment shortcuts on top of vanilla scroll behavior.
[list]
[*][b]Plain scroll[/b]: vanilla. Advances the hotbar / inventory selection.
[*][b]Ctrl + scroll[/b]: cycles cartridges on the held Advanced Tablet. Auto-equips a tablet from off-hand, toolbelt, backpack, or suit if none is in the active hand.
[*][b]LeftShift + scroll[/b]: cycles sensor chips on the worn Sensor Lenses (no auto-equip).
[*][b]Ctrl + LeftShift + scroll[/b]: tightens (wheel-up) or widens (wheel-down) the worn helmet's spotlight. Configurable under [b]Client - Helmet Beam[/b] settings.
[*][b]RightShift + scroll[/b]: vanilla camera zoom + first/third-person toggle. Auto-rebound from LeftShift (see below).
[/list]

For tablets and lenses, wheel-down past the first occupied slot turns the device OFF without losing the active index, and wheel-up from OFF restores the last selection.

[h2]Camera-zoom key auto-rebind[/h2]
Stationeers binds first/third-person camera zoom to LeftShift by default, which conflicts with the LeftShift+scroll lens binding. On first launch, EquipmentPlus rebinds the camera-zoom key to RightShift and saves the change to your settings file. [b]Hold the RIGHT shift, not the left, for camera zoom.[/b] If you have already customized this binding to anything other than LeftShift, EquipmentPlus leaves it alone.

[h2]Compatibility[/h2]

[b]Requires:[/b]
[list]
[*][url=https://docs.bepinex.dev/]BepInEx[/url]
[*][url=https://github.com/StationeersLaunchPad/StationeersLaunchPad]StationeersLaunchPad[/url]
[/list]

[b]Incompatible with[/b] (detected at startup; the mod refuses to load if any are found):
[list]
[*][url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3134483503]Better Advanced Tablet[/url] by Serialtasted (redundant; this mod replaces it)
[*][url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3651839114]ImprovedConfiguration[/url] by Doggo (redundant; this mod replaces it with multiplayer support)
[*][url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3578912665]Slot Configuration Cartridge[/url] by Otis B. (absorbed; logic slot display is now built in)
[/list]

[b]All players[/b] on a server must have Equipment Plus installed. Matching mod versions are enforced during the connection handshake automatically.

[b]Dedicated servers[/b] need the same BepInEx + StationeersLaunchPad + EquipmentPlus setup installed server-side.

[h2]Reporting Issues[/h2]
If you run into a bug or something behaves unexpectedly, please open an issue on [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/issues]GitHub[/url]. Please include the mod name in the title so reports can be triaged. Steam comment notifications don't always come through, so GitHub is the reliable way to make sure a report is seen.

[h2]Credits[/h2]
Inspired by [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3134483503]Better Advanced Tablet[/url] by Serialtasted and spacebuilder2020 and [url=https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=3651839114]ImprovedConfiguration[/url] by Doggo.

[url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/tree/master/Mods/EquipmentPlus]Source Code on GitHub[/url]

[h2]License[/h2]
Licensed under the [url=https://github.com/SixFive7/StationeersPlus/blob/master/LICENSE]Apache License 2.0[/url]. Attribution required; see the LICENSE and NOTICE files at the repository root.</Description>
  <ChangeLog>
v1.0.0: Initial release
- Dynamic multi-slot support for Sensor Lenses and the Advanced Tablet (slots grow as you fill them, shrink as you empty them; exactly one empty slot visible at all times)
- Multiplayer-safe Configuration Cartridge editing (scroll to select a line, left-click to copy read-only values or edit writable values; both LogicType and per-slot LogicSlotType writes work from any client via vanilla SetLogicFromClient and a custom SetLogicSlotFromClient message)
- Built-in logic slot display on the Config Cartridge screen (writable in grey, read-only in green), absorbing Slot Configuration Cartridge
- Scroll-modifier equipment shortcuts: Ctrl + scroll cycles tablet cartridges (auto-equips a tablet from off-hand, toolbelt, backpack, or suit when the active hand is empty); LeftShift + scroll cycles worn sensor chips; Ctrl + LeftShift + scroll tightens/widens the worn helmet's spotlight (auto-brightness scales intensity and range; configurable via Client - Helmet Beam settings)
- Vanilla camera zoom auto-rebound from LeftShift to RightShift on first launch to free LeftShift for the lens cycle binding (custom bindings are respected; only the LeftShift default is replaced). Hold the RIGHT shift for camera zoom.
- Active sensor chip and active tablet cartridge persist across save/load and sync across peers in multiplayer
- Per-character helmet beam preferences persist across save/load (each player's spot angle, intensity, and range survive a reload; on join, the host pushes the current beam map to the connecting client)
- Save persistence uses side-car files inside the save ZIP (no xsi:type extension to world.xml), so uninstalling EquipmentPlus never breaks an existing save
- Full multiplayer support; matching mod versions enforced during the connection handshake
- Startup conflict detection for Better Advanced Tablet, ImprovedConfiguration, Slot Configuration Cartridge, and Better Headlamp; the mod refuses to load if any of those are enabled and logs an ongoing warning
  </ChangeLog>
  <WorkshopHandle>0</WorkshopHandle>
  <Tags>
    <Tag>BepInEx</Tag>
    <Tag>StationeersLaunchPad</Tag>
    <Tag>sensor</Tag>
    <Tag>tablet</Tag>
    <Tag>multiplayer</Tag>
  </Tags>
  <InGameDescription><![CDATA[<size="30"><color=#ffa500>Equipment Plus</color></size>
<line-height=40%>Adds dynamic multi-slot sensor lenses and advanced tablets to Stationeers, with multiplayer-safe configuration cartridge enhancements.
Full multiplayer compatibility. Safe to remove from existing savegames.
<b>How it works:</b>
Insert a chip or cartridge and a new empty slot appears.
Remove items and excess empty slots disappear.
Always exactly one empty slot visible. No clutter.
<b>Supported:</b>
- Sensor Lenses (all sensor chips)
- Advanced Tablet (all cartridges)
<b>Scroll modifiers:</b>
- Ctrl + scroll: cycle tablet cartridges (auto-equips a tablet from your inventory)
- LeftShift + scroll: cycle worn lens chips
- Ctrl + LeftShift + scroll: tighten/widen helmet spotlight
- RightShift + scroll: vanilla camera zoom (auto-rebound from LeftShift on first launch; hold the RIGHT shift)
<b>Config Cartridge:</b> Scroll to select a line, left-click to copy read-only values or edit writable values. Works in multiplayer.
Logic slot values are shown below the logic values (grey = writable, green = read-only). Scroll and click to read or edit slot values too.
<b>Requires:</b> BepInEx + StationeersLaunchPad. All players must have this mod installed.
</line-height>
]]></InGameDescription>
</ModMetadata>
